<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Health on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Health on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Pollution</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution sensors are devices that detect and monitor the presence of air pollution of the environment. The majority focuses on components: ozone, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, sulfur dioxide, and nitrous oxide.  Wikipedia     Research Array of Things
 
PM2.5 refers to atmospheric particulate matter (PM) that have a diameter of less than 2.5 micrometers. Such particles are able to bypass the nose and throat and penetrate deep into the lungs and some may even enter the circulatory system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECG</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</guid>
      <description>Electrocardiography is the process of recording the electrical activity of the heart over a period of time using electrodes placed on the skin.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Smart Healthcare, Arrhythmia Detection, Low-cost Monitoring, Real-time Monitoring
 
Maker Hackster: RPi+Azure+AD8232, Hackaday: Arduino+ECGShield
 
ECG records the electrical activity generated by heart muscle depolarizations, which propagate in pulsating electrical waves towards the skin. Although the electricity amount is in fact very small, it can be picked up reliably with ECG electrodes attached to the skin (data unit: microvolt, uV).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedometer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</guid>
      <description>A pedometer is a device, usually portable and electronic or electromechanical, that counts each step a person takes by detecting the motion of the person&amp;#39;s hands or hips.  Wikipedia     Research Comparing 13 Pedometer Models, Accuracy for Children, How Many Steps Per Day?, Intensity Classification
 
Popular Devices Fitbit, Apple Watch, Nike+, iPod Nano
 
The technology for a pedometer includes a mechanical sensor and software to count steps.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>