<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Internet of Things Landscape on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Internet of Things Landscape on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:30:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/arduino/</guid>
      <description>Arduino is an open source single-board microcontroller for building digital devices and interactive objects that can sense and control objects in the physical world. Arduino boards are available commercially in preassembled form, or as do-it-yourself kits.  Wikipedia     Research Agriculture: Soil Moisture Monitoring
Smart City/Smart Home: Smart Garbage, $30 Home Automation System, Environmental Monitoring
Industry: Smart Supply Chain
 
Series Comparison &amp;hellip;    Arduino CPU SRAM Flash     Yún 400 MHz 64 MB 16 MB   Uno 16 MHz 2 KB 32 KB   101 32 MHz 24 KB 196 KB   Micro 16 MHz 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth is a wireless technology standard for exchanging data over short distances (using short-wavelength UHF radio waves in the industrial, scientific and medical (ISM) radio bands from 2.4 to 2.485 GHz) from fixed and mobile devices, and building personal area networks (PANs). Bluetooth Low Energy or Smart is intended to provide considerably reduced power consumption and cost while maintaining a similar communication range.  Wikipedia     Feature Compare &amp;hellip;    Feature BT-LE BT     Audio/Headset No Yes   Data Yes Yes   A/V Control Non-Native Native   Throughput Low Medium   Authentication No For Non-Audio Only</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</guid>
      <description>CoAP is a specialised web transfer protocol for use with constrained nodes and constrained (e.g., low-power, lossy) networks.  RFC 7252     Research HTTP/2, CoAP on device HTTP/2 everywhere else, Security, Californium Cloud Services, MQTT vs CoAP, TinyOS Performance, Transport: Logistics
 
CoAP is network-oriented protocol with similar features to HTTP but also allows for low overhead, multicast, etc. CoAP operates over UDP (simpler) instead of TCP compensating for unreliability with a retransmission mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRaWAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lora/</guid>
      <description>LoRaWAN is a Low Power Wide Area Network (LPWAN) specification intended for wireless battery operated Things in a regional, national or global network. It is designed to allow low-powered devices to communicate with Internet-connected applications over long range wireless connections.  lora-alliance.org     The Things Network The Things Network is a first-of-its-kind system that uses low-power, low-bandwidth LoRaWAN technology to cover the city with a wireless signal that allows objects like boats, trash cans and street lights to become tools for developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a publish-subscribe-based lightweight messaging protocol for use on top of TCP/IP. It is designed for connections where a small code footprint is required or the network bandwidth is limited.  Wikipedia     Research CoAP vs MQTT, MQTT and REST, Push Notifications, Secure MQTT
 
MQTT-SN is a variation of the main protocol aimed at embedded devices on non-TCP/IP networks, such as ZigBee. As it does not require the TCP/IP stack, it can be used over a serial link where overhead is really small or over UDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbit</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/microbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/microbit/</guid>
      <description>The BBC Micro Bit is an ARM-based embedded system designed by the BBC for use in computer education. The board is 4 cm × 5 cm and has an ARM Cortex-M0 processor, accelerometer and magnetometer sensors, Bluetooth and USB connectivity, a display consisting of 25 LEDs, two programmable buttons, and can be powered by either USB or an external battery pack.  Wikipedia     Hardware  Size: 43 mm × 52 mm (half credit card)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPi</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/rpi/</guid>
      <description>The Raspberry Pi is a series of popular small and low-cost single-board computers. It was first developed in the UK by the Raspberry Pi Foundation. Manifold products have been created to accompany, modify, and enhance the Pi’s capabilities.  Wikipedia     Research Health Monitoring, Web of Things Book, Industrial Automation, Environmental Monitoring
 
Series Comparison    RPi CPU RAM WiFi     3 4 x 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zigbee</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</guid>
      <description>Zigbee is an IEEE 802.15.4-based specification for a suite of high-level communication protocols used to create personal area networks with small, low-power digital radios, such as for home automation, medical device data collection, and other low-power low-bandwidth needs, designed for small scale projects which need wireless connection.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.15.4 IEEE 802.15.4 is a technical standard which defines the operation of low-rate wireless personal area networks (LR-WPANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1888.3</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/18883-green-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/18883-green-security/</guid>
      <description>Green Security is a new research field defining and investigating security solutions under an energy-aware perspective. 1888.3 describes the enhanced security management function for the IEEE 1888 &amp;#39;Ubiquitous Green Community Control Network Protocol&amp;#39;.  IEEE     Research Smart meter, Efficient Power Grid Algorithms, Proxy, Survey on Protocols and Standards, Real-time Smart Grid
 
Ubiquitous computing (or &amp;ldquo;ubicomp&amp;rdquo;) is a concept in software engineering and computer science where computing is made to appear anytime and everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6LoWPAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/6lowpan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/6lowpan/</guid>
      <description>The 6LoWPAN concept originated from the idea that &amp;#39;the Internet Protocol could and should be applied even to the smallest devices,&amp;#39; and that low-power devices with limited processing capabilities should be able to participate in the Internet of Things. The 6LoWPAN group has defined encapsulation and header compression mechanisms that allow IPv6 packets to be sent and received over IEEE 802.15.4 (LR-WPAN) based networks.  Wikipedia     Thread Thread is a standard suggested by Nest Labs based on IEEE 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>802.15.4</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/802-15-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/802-15-4/</guid>
      <description>IEEE 802.15.4 is a technical standard which defines the operation of low-rate wireless personal area networks (LR-WPANs). It specifies the physical layer and media access control for LR-WPANs, and is maintained by the IEEE 802.15 working group, which defined the standard in 2003.  Wikipedia     Features  Data rates of 250 kbps, 40 kbps, and 20 kbps.
 Two addressing modes; 16-bit short and 64-bit IEEE addressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AMQP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/amqp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/amqp/</guid>
      <description>The Advanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP) is an open standard application layer protocol for message-oriented middleware. The defining features of AMQP are message orientation, queuing, routing (including point-to-point and publish-and-subscribe), reliability and security.  Wikipedia     Architecture 
 
Network Protocol 
 
AMQP is a binary, application layer protocol, designed to efficiently support a wide variety of messaging applications and communication patterns. It provides flow controlled, message-oriented communication with message-delivery guarantees such as at-most-once (where each message is delivered once or never), at-least-once (where each message is certain to be delivered, but may do so multiple times) and exactly-once (where the message will always certainly arrive and do so only once), and authentication and/or encryption based on SASL and/or TLS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANGELS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/angels/</guid>
      <description>ANGELS is a work in progress research project that explores the idea of utilising smart edge devices for performing certain portions of the data analysis tasks in IoT.  Wikipedia     Abstract The current global emphasis on “Internet of Things (IoT)” have highlighted the extreme importance of sensor-based intelligent and ubiquitous systems which are more commonly known as “cyber-physical systems.” The technology has the potential to create a network of smart devices and things to an extent that has never been envisaged before, far outnumbering the number of devices connected in the Internet as we know today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANT&#43;</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</guid>
      <description>ANT&amp;#43; is a wireless protocol for monitoring sensor data such as a person&amp;#39;s heart rate or a car&amp;#39;s tyre/tire pressure, as well as the control of systems like indoor lighting or a television set.  Wikipedia     
 
ANT is a practical wireless sensor network protocol running in the 2.4 GHz ISM band. Designed for ultra-low power, ease of use, efficiency and scalability, ANT easily handles peer-to-peer, star, connected star, tree and fixed mesh topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Things</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/android-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/android-things/</guid>
      <description>Android Things (codenamed/rebranded from Brillo) is an Android-based embedded operating system platform by Google. It is aimed to be used with low-power and memory constrained Internet of Things (IoT) devices, which are usually built from different microcontroller platforms.  Wikipedia     Like updates for Android Phones, developers can push Google-provided OS updates and custom app updates using the same over-the-air infrastructure that Google uses for its products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beagle</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/beagle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/beagle/</guid>
      <description>Beagles are low-cost, fan-less single-board computers based on low-power Texas Instruments processors featuring the ARM Cortex-A series core with all of the expandability of today&amp;#39;s desktop machines, but without the bulk, expense, or noise. Initially, development was targeted at enabling Linux distributions to improve support for ARM devices.  BeagleBoard.org     BeagleBone VS BeagleBone Black 
 elinux.org    
BeagleBoard The USB-powered BeagleBoard is a low-cost, fan-less single board computer that unleashes laptop-like performance and expandability without the bulk, expense, or noise of typical desktop machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSI</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/csi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/csi/</guid>
      <description>The goal of the Container Storage Interface (CSI) is to define and interface that will enable storage vendors to develop a plugin once and have it work across a number of container orchestration (CO) systems.  CSI community     The CSI specification is an emerging specification that defines an interface along with the minimum operational and packaging recommendations for a storage provider (SP) to implement a CSI compatible plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/ceph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/ceph/</guid>
      <description>Ceph is a free-software storage platform that implements object storage on a single distributed computer cluster, and provides interfaces for object-, block- and file-level storage. Ceph aims primarily for completely distributed operation without a single point of failure, scalable to the exabyte level, and freely available. As a result of its design, the system is both self-healing and self-managing, aiming to minimize administration time and other costs.  Wikipedia         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOx</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cisco-iox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cisco-iox/</guid>
      <description>IOx combines IoT application execution within the fog and offers highly secure connectivity with Cisco IOS technology, as well as powerful services for rapid, reliable integration with IoT sensors and the cloud.  cisco.com     Architecture 
 cisco.com    
The Cisco IOx application environment combines IoT application execution within the fog; secure connectivity with Cisco IOS Software; and powerful services for rapid, reliable integration with Internet of Things (IoT) sensors and the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudlet</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cloudlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cloudlet/</guid>
      <description>A cloudlet is a mobility-enhanced small-scale cloud datacenter that is located at the edge of the Internet. The main purpose of the cloudlet is supporting resource-intensive and interactive mobile applications by providing powerful computing resources to mobile devices with lower latency. It is a new architectural element that extends today’s cloud computing infrastructure.  Wikipedia     Cloudlet VS Cloud There is significant overlap in the requirements for cloud and cloudlet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoRE RD</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/core/</guid>
      <description>In many M2M applications, direct discovery of resources is not practical due to sleeping nodes, disperse networks, or networks where multicast traffic is inefficient. These problems can be solved by employing an entity called a Resource Directory (RD), which hosts descriptions of resources held on other servers, allowing lookups to be performed for those resources.  IETF.org Draft     Introduction The discovery of resources offered by a constrained server is very important in machine-to-machine applications where there are no humans in the loop and static interfaces result in fragility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computes.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/computes-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/computes-io/</guid>
      <description>Computes.io is a mesh networked, distributed supercomputing platform powered by IPFS. Each node on the mesh network acts as both a core and kernel, meaning that each node can perform computations for other machines as well as request computations from itself and other machines.  computes.io     Computes.io is a distributed supercomputer mesh network. Each node on the mesh network acts as both a core and kernel — meaning that each node can perform Javascript computations for other machines as well as request computations from itself and other machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contiki</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/contiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/contiki/</guid>
      <description>An open source operating system for the Internet of Things. Contiki connects tiny low-cost, low-power microcontrollers to the Internet. Contiki is a powerful toolbox for building complex wireless systems.  contiki-os.org     Research vs TinyOS, IoT-Lab Testbed, WSN OS Comparisons
 
Programming on Contiki is done using the Cooja network simulator. To program, control and monitor the remote IoT devices, the back-end C base libraries of RFID chips and sensors can be customised and recompiled to get the desired results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CubieBoard</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/cubieboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/cubieboard/</guid>
      <description>Cubieboard is a single-board computer which can run Android 4 ICS, Ubuntu 12.04 desktop, Fedora 19 ARM Remix desktop, Arch Linux ARM, a Debian-based Cubian distribution, or OpenBSD. It uses the AllWinner A10 SoC, popular on cheap tablets, phones and media PCs. This SoC is used by developers of the lima driver, an open-source driver for the ARM Mali GPU.  Wikipedia     Cubietruck Plus (Cubieboard 5) Hardware (More Models)  SoC: Allwinner H8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DASH7</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/dash7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/dash7/</guid>
      <description>DASH7 Alliance Protocol (D7A) is an open source Wireless Sensor and Actuator Network protocol, which operates in the 433 MHz, 868 MHz and 915 MHz unlicensed ISM band/SRD band. DASH7 provides multi-year battery life, range of up to 2 km, low latency for connecting with moving things, a very small open source protocol stack, AES 128-bit shared key encryption support, and data transfer of up to 167 kbit/s.  Wikipedia     Why DASH7?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DDS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/dds/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/dds/</guid>
      <description>The Data Distribution Service for real-time systems (DDS) is an Object Management Group (OMG) machine-to-machine (sometimes called middleware) standard that aims to enable scalable, real-time, dependable, high-performance and interoperable data exchanges using a publish–subscribe pattern. DDS addresses the needs of applications like financial trading, air-traffic control, smart grid management, and other big data applications. The standard is used in applications such as smartphone operating systems, transportation systems and vehicles, software-defined radio, and by healthcare providers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS-SD</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/dns-sd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/dns-sd/</guid>
      <description>DNS-SD allows clients to discover a named list of service instances, given a service type, and to resolve those services to hostnames using standard DNS queries. The specification is compatible with existing unicast DNS server and client software, but works equally well with Multicast DNS in a zero-configuration environment.  Wikipedia     Zeroconf It is a set of technologies that automatically creates a usable computer network based on TCP/IP when computers or network peripherals are interconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Harvesting</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/energy-harvesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/energy-harvesting/</guid>
      <description>Energy harvesting or scavenging is the process by which ambient energy is derived from external sources, captured, and stored for small, wireless autonomous devices.  Wikipedia     Research Parametric Excitation, Energy Harvesting Technologies Book, Wireless Energy Harvesting, Comparison
 
Makers Solar Harvesting Project, Pieze, Wurth, Energy Harvesting Designs for the IoT
 
All processes that involve energy conversion are, to some degree, inefficient. Motors get hot, as do power transistors, automobile engines, and light bulbs; in each case energy is wasted as heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ethernet</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/ethernet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/ethernet/</guid>
      <description>Ethernet is a family of computer networking technologies commonly used in local area networks (LAN), metropolitan area networks (MAN) and wide area networks (WAN). It was commercially introduced in 1980 and first standardized in 1983 as IEEE 802.3, and has since been refined to support higher bit rates and longer link distances.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.3 IEEE 802.3 is a working group and a collection of Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) standards produced by the working group defining the physical layer and data link layer&amp;rsquo;s media access control (MAC) of wired Ethernet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eywa</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Eywa is an interoperable fog computing infrastructure for RDF Stream Processing (RSP). It implements a means of distribution and control of query workload for stream processing on flexible, interopeable, RDF graph structures.  eugenesiow.com     Paper Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FireWire</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/firewire/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/firewire/</guid>
      <description>IEEE 1394 is an interface standard for a serial bus for high-speed communications and isochronous real-time data transfer. It was developed in the late 1980s and early 1990s by Apple, which called it FireWire. The 1394 interface is also known by the brand i.LINK (Sony), and Lynx (Texas Instruments).  Wikipedia     FireWire can connect up to 63 peripherals in a tree or daisy-chain topology (as opposed to Parallel SCSI&amp;rsquo;s electrical bus topology).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FusionFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/fusionfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/fusionfs/</guid>
      <description>FusionFS is a distributed filesystem that co-exists with current parallel filesystems in High-End Computing, optimized for both a subset of HPC and Many-Task Computing workloads. FusionFS is a user-level filesystem that runs on the compute resource infrastructure, and enables every compute node to actively participate in the metadata and data management. Distributed metadata management is implemented using ZHT, a zero-hop distributed hashtable.  datasys.cs.iit.edu     Abstract State-of-the-art, yet decades-old, architecture of high-performance computing systems has its compute and storage resources separated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPRS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/gprs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/gprs/</guid>
      <description>General Packet Radio Service (GPRS) is a packet oriented mobile data service on the 2G and 3G cellular communication system&amp;#39;s global system for mobile communications (GSM). GPRS is a best-effort service, implying variable throughput and latency that depend on the number of other users sharing the service concurrently.  Wikipedia     In 2G systems, GPRS provides data rates of 56–114 kbit/second. 2G cellular technology combined with GPRS is sometimes described as 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSM</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/gsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/gsm/</guid>
      <description>GSM (Global System for Mobile Communications, originally Groupe Spécial Mobile) is a standard developed by the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (ETSI) to describe the protocols for second-generation digital cellular networks used by mobile devices such as tablets. The GSM standard originally described as a digital, circuit-switched network optimized for full duplex voice telephony. This expanded over time to include data communications, first by circuit-switched transport, then by packet data transport via GPRS (General Packet Radio Services) and EDGE (Enhanced Data rates for GSM Evolution, or EGPRS).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gadgeteer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gadgeteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gadgeteer/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft .NET Gadgeteer is an open-source rapid-prototyping standard for building small electronic devices using the Microsoft .NET Micro Framework and Microsoft Visual Studio/Visual C# Express. The Gadgeteer platform centers around a Gadgeteer mainboard with a microcontroller running the .NET Micro Framework.  Wikipedia     .NET Gadgeteer was created by researchers at Microsoft as an internal prototyping tool, but because of external interest, particualrly from educators and hobbyists, we turned it into open source software which now has a vibrant hardware ecosystem from multiple manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galileo</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/galileo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/galileo/</guid>
      <description>Intel Galileo is the first in a line of Arduino-certified development boards based on Intel x86 architecture and is designed for the maker and education communities. Intel released two versions of Galileo, referred to as Gen 1 and Gen 2. These development boards are sometimes called &amp;#39;Breakout boards&amp;#39;.  Wikipedia     Intel Galileo combines Intel technology with support for Arduino ready-made hardware expansion cards (called &amp;ldquo;shields&amp;rdquo;) and the Arduino software development environment and libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gizmo2</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gizmo2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gizmo2/</guid>
      <description>Gizmo2 is the second generation open source x86 development board from GizmoSphere. Gizmo 2 provides the power of a high performance computer and the I/O capabilities of a microcontroller through the use of an AMD Embedded G-Series System-on-Chip (SOC). The board includes the AMD GX-210HA dual-core processor, combined on a single die with AMD Radeon HD 8210E discrete-class graphics, providing 85 GFLOPS performance while drawing only 9 watts TDP.  element14     The new Gizmo 2 platform is the second-generation x86-based DIY single-board-computer (SBC) from Gizmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GlusterFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/glusterfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/glusterfs/</guid>
      <description>GlusterFS is a scale-out network-attached storage file system. It has found applications including cloud computing, streaming media services, and content delivery networks. GlusterFS was developed originally by Gluster, Inc. and then by Red Hat, Inc., as a result of Red Hat acquiring Gluster in 2011. Red Hat Gluster Storage is a GlusterFS-based Red Hat Storage Server.  Wikipedia         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/han/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/han/</guid>
      <description>A home network or home area network (HAN) is a type of computer network that facilitates communication among devices within the close vicinity of a home. Devices capable of participating in this network, for example, smart devices such as network printers and handheld mobile computers, often gain enhanced emergent capabilities through their ability to interact.  Wikipedia     A home-area network (HAN) connects in-home digital devices, such as PCs, mobile phones, entertainment technology, thermostats, home security systems and smart appliances, into a common network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HDFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/hdfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/hdfs/</guid>
      <description>The Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) is a distributed file system designed to run on commodity hardware. HDFS is highly fault-tolerant and is designed to be deployed on low-cost hardware. HDFS provides high throughput access to application data and is suitable for applications that have large data sets. HDFS relaxes a few POSIX requirements to enable streaming access to file system data.  apache.org         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/http2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/http2/</guid>
      <description>HTTP/2 is a major revision of the HTTP network protocol used by the World Wide Web and derived from Google&amp;#39;s earlier experimental SPDY protocol.  Wikipedia     Research HTTP/1.1 pipelining vs HTTP2 in-the-clear, HTTP/2 multiplexed stream, HTTP/2 in Web Services
 
HTTP/2 Server Push allows you to send site assets to the user before they’ve even asked for them. It’s an elegant way to achieve the performance benefits of HTTP/1 optimization practices such as inlining, but without the drawbacks that come with that practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypercat</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/hypercat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/hypercat/</guid>
      <description>The Hypercat specification allows Internet of Things (IoT) clients to discover information about IoT assets over the web. With Hypercat developers can write applications that will work across many servers, breaking down the walls between vertical silos.  Hypercat.io     Reference Server (Code)  GET, PUT, POST, DELETE of items
 Multi-search
 Geo search
 Lexicographic search
 Simple search
 Prefix search
 Authentication</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/ipfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/ipfs/</guid>
      <description>InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a protocol designed to create a permanent and decentralized method of storing and sharing files. It is a content-addressable, peer-to-peer hypermedia distribution protocol. Nodes in the IPFS network form a distributed file system.  Wikipedia     IPNS IPFS has a name service called IPNS, a global namespace based on PKI, serves to build trust chains, is compatible with other NSes and can map DNS, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPsec</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/ipsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/ipsec/</guid>
      <description>IPsec is a network protocol suite that authenticates and encrypts the packets of data sent over a network. IPsec includes protocols for establishing mutual authentication between agents at the beginning of the session and negotiation of cryptographic keys to use during the session.  Wikipedia     Specifications RFC 4301 defines a Security Architecture for the Internet Protocol, while RFC 4303 defines the Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) protocol and RFC 4309 describes the use of Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) in Counter with CBC-MAC (CCM) Mode as an IPsec Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IR</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ir/</guid>
      <description>Infrared radiation, or simply infrared or IR, is electromagnetic radiation (EMR) with longer wavelengths than those of visible light, and is therefore invisible, although it is sometimes loosely called infrared light. IR data transmission is employed in short-range communication among computer peripherals and personal digital assistants.  Wikipedia     IrDA IrDA refers to a complete set of protocols for wireless infrared communications. The main reason for using IrDA had been wireless data transfer over the “last one meter” using point-and-shoot principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ISM</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/ism/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/ism/</guid>
      <description>The ISM radio bands are radio bands (portions of the radio spectrum) reserved internationally for the use of radio frequency (RF) energy for industrial, scientific and medical purposes other than telecommunications. Examples of applications in these bands include radio-frequency process heating, microwave ovens, and medical diathermy machines. The powerful emissions of these devices can create electromagnetic interference and disrupt radio communication using the same frequency, so these devices were limited to certain bands of frequencies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insteon</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/insteon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/insteon/</guid>
      <description>Insteon is a home automation technology that enables light switches, lights, thermostats, leak sensors, remote controls, motion sensors, and other electrically powered devices to interoperate through power lines, radio frequency (RF) communications, or both. It employs a dual-mesh networking topology in which all devices are peers and each device independently transmits, receives, and repeats messages.  Wikipedia     Insteon Hub Insteon Hub is a simple and straightforward device that connects you to your home from any smartphone or tablet, anywhere in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LTE</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lte/</guid>
      <description>LTE is a standard for high-speed wireless communication for mobile devices and data terminals, based on the GSM/EDGE and UMTS/HSPA technologies. It increases the capacity and speed using a different radio interface together with core network improvements. The standard is developed by the 3GPP (3rd Generation Partnership Project).  Wikipedia     NB-IoT &amp;hellip; NarrowBand IoT (NB-IoT) is a Low Power Wide Area Network (LPWAN) radio technology standard. NB-IoT focuses specifically on indoor coverage, low cost, long battery life, and enabling a large number of connected devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiteOS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/lite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/lite/</guid>
      <description>LiteOS is a Unix-like operating system that fits on memory-constrained sensor nodes. LiteOS provides a familiar programming environment based on Unix, threads, and C. It follows a hybrid programming model that allows both event-driven and thread-driven programming.  Wikipedia     Research Original LiteOS Paper, Interactive UNIX Shell Demo Paper, Event Traces in the LiteOS
 
Huawei also developed an open-source operating system for the IoT called Huawei LiteOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lustre</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/lustre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/lustre/</guid>
      <description>Lustre is a type of parallel distributed file system, generally used for large-scale cluster computing. The name Lustre is a portmanteau word derived from Linux and cluster. Lustre file system software is available under the GNU GPLv2 and provides high performance file systems for computer clusters ranging in size from small workgroup clusters to large-scale, multi-site clusters.  Wikipedia and opensfs.org         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mbed OS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/mbed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/mbed/</guid>
      <description>Arm Mbed OS is an open source embedded operating system designed specifically for the &amp;#39;things&amp;#39; in the Internet of Things. It includes all the features you need to develop a connected product based on an Arm Cortex-M microcontroller, including security, connectivity, an RTOS, and drivers for sensors and I/O devices.  mbed.com     Mbed Cloud Mbed Cloud is a suite of software tools and services for developing secure IoT products, including secure communication, standard-based and seamless device management and flexible production-line integration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Charging</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/motion-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/motion-charging/</guid>
      <description>Motion-powered charging involves the transformation of naturally occurring motion in the form of kinetic energy into electricity which can be used to charge batteries and power electronic devices.   Research Copenhagen Wheel, Vint Cerf&amp;rsquo;s Taking the Internet to the Next Physical Level, Self-charging Textile
 
Ampy Move is a wearable motion-charger that transforms the kinetic energy from motion into power for smartphone and wearables. Inductors in the Move device transform movement into usable power to charge devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multicast CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/multicast-coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/multicast-coap/</guid>
      <description>Group communication involves a one-to-many relationship between CoAP endpoints. Specifically, a single CoAP client can simultaneously get (or set) resources from multiple CoAP servers using CoAP over IP multicast. CoAP is a web transfer protocol based on Representational State Transfer (REST) for resource constrained devices operating in an IP network.  RFC 7390     In M2M applications, for example, home or building automation, there is a need for local clients and servers to find and interact with each other without human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NFC</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/nfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/nfc/</guid>
      <description>Near-field communication (NFC) is a set of communication protocols that enable two electronic devices, one of which is usually a portable device such as a smartphone, to establish communication by bringing them within 4 cm (1.6 in) of each other. NFC offers a low-speed connection with simple setup that can be used to bootstrap more capable wireless connections.  Wikipedia     NFC Protocol Stack Overview</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUC</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/nuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/nuc/</guid>
      <description>Next Unit of Computing (NUC) is a small-form-factor personal computer designed by Intel. Its motherboard measures 4 × 4 inches (10.16 × 10.16 cm). The barebone kits consist of the board, in a plastic case with a fan, an external power supply and VESA mounting plate.  Wikipedia     Seventh Generation Intel&amp;rsquo;s seventh generation NUC models, codenamed Baby Canyon, are based on their Kaby Lake-U processors with a TDP from 15 W to 28 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>P1906.1</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/p1906-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/p1906-1/</guid>
      <description>The IEEE P1906.1 - Recommended Practice for Nanoscale and Molecular Communication Framework - is a standards working group sponsored by the IEEE Communications Society Standards Development Board whose goal is to develop a common framework for nanoscale and molecular communication.  Wikipedia     A nanoscale communication network is a human-designed system for communicating at or with the nanoscale, using physical principles that are suited to nanoscale systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIOTRe</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/piotre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/piotre/</guid>
      <description>PIOTRe is a Personal IoT Repository that allows applications to be built on interoperable and efficient semantic database technology for deployment on lightweight IoT devices. The name PIOTRe is derived from the name Peter meaning &amp;#39;stone&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;rock&amp;#39; and is the foundation for personal IoT device repositories.  cisco.com     Architecture 
 cisco.com    
PIOTRe PIOTRe is a Personal IoT Repository based on sparql2sql, sparql2stream and sparql2fed technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phidgets</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/phidgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/phidgets/</guid>
      <description>Phidgets are a system of low-cost electronic components and sensors that are controlled by a personal computer. Using the Universal Serial Bus (USB) as the basis for all phidgets, the complexity is managed behind an Application Programming Interface (API). A phidget is a physical representation or implementation of a GUI widget.  Wikipedia     Phidgets are an easy to use set of building blocks for low cost sensing and control from your PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPL</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/rpl/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/rpl/</guid>
      <description>RPL is the IPv6 Routing Protocol for Low-Power and Lossy Networks (LLN), which provides a mechanism whereby multipoint-to-point traffic from devices inside the LLN towards a central control point as well as point-to-multipoint traffic from the central control point to the devices inside the LLN are supported.  RFC 6550     RPL is a distance vector routing protocol for LLNs that makes use of IPv6. Network devices running the protocol are connected in such a way that no cycles are present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resin.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/resin-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/resin-io/</guid>
      <description>Resin.io offers a development and deployment framework based upon Linux and containers that is designed to facilitate control of the on-device environment, provision devices on the network, and manage a fleet of systems.  resin.io     The Good  Developer friendly: iterate and push
 20 supported maker devices
 Container-based
 Open Source: ResinOS, Balena
 First 10 devices free
   
   Features &amp;hellip;     Control on-device environment   Provision devices easily   Manage device fleet at scale   Automate device fleet from own cloud   Encrypted communication   Continuous updates</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riot OS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/riot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/riot/</guid>
      <description>RIOT is a small operating system for networked, memory-constrained systems with a focus on low-power wireless IoT devices. It is open-source software, released under the GNU Lesser General Public License (LGPL). Due to its large independent community RIOT is often referred to as the Linux of the Internet of Things.  Wikipedia     RIOT is an operating system designed for the particular requirements of Internet of Things (IoT) scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/san/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/san/</guid>
      <description>A SAN is a network which provides access to consolidated, block level data storage. SANs are primarily used to enhance storage devices, such as disk arrays, tape libraries, and optical jukeboxes, accessible to servers so that the devices appear to the operating system as locally attached devices. A SAN typically has its own network of storage devices that are generally not accessible through the local area network (LAN) by other devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIR</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/sir/</guid>
      <description>The Sensor Instance Registry (SIR) is a web service interface for managing sensor catalogues. It is based on the OGC discussion paper 10-171 and 09-163r2 (SensorML discovery profile) and presents a pragmatic solution that may serve as the basis for further discussion and development. The paper contains extensive descriptions of the service operations (requests and responses) for GET and POST requests.  52north.org     SensorML discovery profile (Paper) This Discussion Paper describes the mapping of sensor metadata encoded following SensorML specification 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSDP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/ssdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/ssdp/</guid>
      <description>The Simple Service Discovery Protocol (SSDP) is a network protocol based on the Internet Protocol Suite for advertisement and discovery of network services and presence information. It accomplishes this without assistance of server-based configuration mechanisms, such as the Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) or the Domain Name System (DNS), and without special static configuration of a network host.  Wikipedia     The Simple Service Discovery Protocol (SSDP) provides a mechanism where by network clients, with little or no static configuration, can discover network services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SensorCloud</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/sensorcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/sensorcloud/</guid>
      <description>SensorCloud is a sensor data storage, visualization and remote management platform. It is a product of LORD MicroStrain Sensing Systems and leverages Cloud computing technologies to provide data scalability, rapid visualization, and user programmable analysis.  sensorcloud.com     MathEngine A $50/month per SensorCloud account account. It provides multiple ways to analyze data. It can generate FFT plots, filter out frequencies, and smooth out noisy data. It also integrates IPython Notebooks into its cloud service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartThings</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/smartthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/smartthings/</guid>
      <description>The SmartThings Hub acts as the centre of a smart home. Able to connect wirelessly with hundreds of compatible smart devices, allowing monitoring, controlling and securing a home from anywhere.  samsung.com     SmartThings primary products include a free SmartThings app, a SmartThings Hub, as well as various sensors and smart devices. The SmartThings native mobile application allows users to control, automate, and monitor their home environment via mobile device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/solid/</guid>
      <description>Solid (derived from &amp;#39;social linked data&amp;#39;) is a proposed set of conventions and tools for building decentralized social applications based on Linked Data principles. The project aims to radically change the way Web applications work today, resulting in true data ownership as well as improved privacy.  computes.io     Apps  Plume Blogging
 Cimba Microblogging
 Contacts
 Dokieli Article Publishing
 Profile Editing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threat Defence</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/threat-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/threat-defence/</guid>
      <description>IoT Threat Defense securely segments IoT devices based on policy that provides an adaptable, extensible means of protecting vital services at IoT scale. It also provides a cybersecurity architecture, featuring a strong cast of integrated products from Identity Services Engine (ISE) and TrustSec to Stealthwatch and Next-Generation Firewall.  cisco.com     IoT Threat Defence works through…  Segmentation
 Secure remote access
 Security services
 Visibility and analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinkerBoard</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/tinkerboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/tinkerboard/</guid>
      <description>The ASUS Tinker Board is a single board computer launched by ASUS in early 2017. Its physical size and GPIO pinout are designed to be compatible with the second-generation and later Raspberry Pi models. The first released board features 4K video, 2GB of onboard RAM, gigabit Ethernet and a Rockchip RK3288 processor running at 1.8 GHz.  Wikipedia     Tinker Board is a Single Board Computer (SBC) in an ultra-small form factor that offers class-leading performance while leveraging outstanding mechanical compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinyOS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/tiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/tiny/</guid>
      <description>TinyOS is an embedded, component-based operating system and platform for low-power wireless devices, such as those used in wireless sensor networks (WSNs), smartdust, ubiquitous computing, personal area networks, building automation, and smart meters.  Wikipedia     Research Original Paper, Hybrid Network Evaluation, Ten-years on Paper
 
Programming on TinyOS is done using a C-like language called nesC. It is a component-based, event-driven programming language with components &amp;ldquo;wired&amp;rdquo; together to run applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPnP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/upnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/upnp/</guid>
      <description>Universal Plug and Play (UPnP) is a set of networking protocols that permits networked devices, such as personal computers, printers, Internet gateways, Wi-Fi access points and mobile devices to seamlessly discover each other&amp;#39;s presence on the network and establish functional network services for data sharing, communications, and entertainment.  Wikipedia     Protocol UPnP assumes the network must run Internet Protocol (IP) and then leverages HTTP, SOAP and XML on top of IP, in order to provide device/service description, actions, data transfer and eventing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UWB</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/uwb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/uwb/</guid>
      <description>Ultra-wideband (also known as UWB, ultra-wide band and ultraband) is a radio technology that can use a very low energy level for short-range, high-bandwidth communications over a large portion of the radio spectrum. UWB transmissions transmit information by generating radio energy at specific time intervals and occupying a large bandwidth, thus enabling pulse-position or time modulation.  Wikipedia     Ultra Wide Band (UWB) is a technology for the transmission of data using techniques which cause a spreading of the radio energy over a very wide frequency band, with a very low power spectral density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VxWorks</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/vxworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/vxworks/</guid>
      <description>VxWorks is a real-time operating system (RTOS) developed as proprietary software and designed for use in embedded systems requiring real-time, deterministic performance and, in many cases, safety and security certification. VxWorks supports Intel (x86, including the new Intel Quark SoC, and x86-64), MIPS, PowerPC, SH-4, and ARM architectures.  Wikipedia     VxWorks comes with the kernel, middleware, board support packages, Wind River Workbench development suite and complementary third-party software and hardware technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Websocket</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/websocket/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/websocket/</guid>
      <description>WebSocket is a computer communications protocol, providing full-duplex communication channels over a single TCP connection. The WebSocket protocol was standardized by the IETF as RFC 6455 in 2011, and the WebSocket API in Web IDL is being standardized by the W3C.  Wikipedia     µWebSockets (Code) µWS is one of the most lightweight, efficient &amp;amp; scalable WebSocket &amp;amp; HTTP server implementations available. It features an easy-to-use, fully async object-oriented interface and scales to millions of connections using only a fraction of memory compared to the competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiFi</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wifi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wifi/</guid>
      <description>Wi-Fi or WiFi is a technology for wireless local area networking with devices based on the IEEE 802.11 standards. A wireless local area network (WLAN) is a wireless computer network that links two or more devices using wireless communication within a limited area such as a home, school, computer laboratory, or office building. Through a gateway, a WLAN can also provide a connection to the wider Internet.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiMAX</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wimax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wimax/</guid>
      <description>WiMAX is a family of wireless communication standards based on the IEEE 802.16 set of standards, which provide multiple physical layer (PHY) and Media Access Control (MAC) options. It can enable wireless usage at long distances.  Wikipedia     Possible Uses  Portable mobile broadband connectivity across cities
 Wireless alternative to cable and DSL for &amp;ldquo;last mile&amp;rdquo; broadband
 Data, telecommunications (VoIP) and IPTV services (triple play)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows IoT</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/windows-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/windows-iot/</guid>
      <description>Windows IoT, formerly Windows Embedded, is a family of operating systems from Microsoft designed for use in embedded systems. Designed specifically for use in small footprint, low-cost devices and IoT scenarios.  Wikipedia     Windows 10 IoT Core A version of Windows optimized for devices that are cost and resource constrained such as IoT gateways, enabling specific industry scenarios and extending the flexibility of Windows 10 offerings to a wider range of specialized devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Charging</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/wireless-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/wireless-charging/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Charging provides a convenient, safe, and reliable way to charge and power electrical devices, IoT sensors and devices, at home, in the workplace and in industry.  powerbyproxi.com     Research Comparing WiTricity and Inductive Coupling History and Future of Wireless Charging, Transport: Inductive Charging for EVs
 
Although inductive charging with an induction coil is the most common form of wireless charging, uBeam is pioneering an ultrasound method, HumaVox uses near-field radio frequency resonance and WiTricity uses Magnetic Resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless USB</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/wireless-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/wireless-usb/</guid>
      <description>Wireless USB is a short-range, high-bandwidth wireless radio communication protocol created by the Wireless USB Promoter Group which intends to further increase the availability of general USB-based technologies. It was designed to operate in the 3.1 to 10.6 GHz frequency range and is capable of sending 480 Mbit/s at distances up to 3 metres (9.8 ft) and 110 Mbit/s at up to 10 metres (33 ft).  Wikipedia     The rationale for this specification is the overwhelming success of USB as a base for peripherals everywhere: cited reasons include extreme ease of use and low cost, which allow the existence of a ubiquitous bidirectional, fast port architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMPP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</guid>
      <description>XMPP is a communications protocol for message-oriented middleware based on XML. It enables the near-real-time exchange of structured yet extensible data between any two or more network entities.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Lightweight IoT Pub/Sub, SmartObjects with mDNS, Cryptographic Hashes
 
XMPP supports different communication patterns, such as Request/Response, Asynchronous Messaging, Publish/Subscribe, Event subscription (Observe) and Delayed delivery. XMPP also has support for different Quality of Service levels for messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xively</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/xively/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/xively/</guid>
      <description>Xively offers an Internet of Things (IoT) platform as a service, business services, and partners that enable businesses to quickly connect products and operations to the Internet. It is a division of LogMeIn Inc.  Wikipedia     Customers Agriculture: Freight Farms, Smart Home: Halo Smart Labs, Lutron, Watts, SureFlap, Industry: Sato, New England Biolabs
 
   Features     Device Management   Identity Management   Device and Cloud Security   Integrations with Enterprise Systems   Remote Device Support</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-Wave</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/z-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/z-wave/</guid>
      <description>Z-Wave is a wireless communications protocol used primarily for home automation. It is a mesh network using low-energy radio waves to communicate from appliance to appliance, allowing for wireless control of residential appliances and other devices, such as lighting control, security systems, thermostats, windows, locks, swimming pools and garage door openers.  Wikipedia     Essentials  Low Powered RF communications technology that supports full mesh networks without the need for a coordinator node</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>digrectory</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/digrectory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/digrectory/</guid>
      <description>A centralized infrastructure that allows registration of sensors. Employs &amp;#39;digrectory&amp;#39; to handle different resources. Each directory is attached to a particular communication technology, such as NFC, IPv6 etc. A mobile app enables users to discover and access sensors. Discovery mechanism takes advantage of geolocation and context awareness.  WoT Group     Architecture 
 
Architecture Components 
 
Abstract The application of Internet-enabled devices in the real world for the development of Smart Cities, environmental monitoring, bus tracking, and parking requires scalability, extensibility, and integration of emerging resources to reach a suitable ecosystem for data acquisition and interaction with citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iRODS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/irods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/irods/</guid>
      <description>The integrated Rule-Oriented Data System (iRODS) is open source data management software used by research organizations and government agencies worldwide. iRODS is released as a production-level distribution aimed at deployment in mission critical environments. It virtualizes data storage resources, so users can take control of their data, regardless of where and on what device the data is stored. As data volumes grow and data services become more complex, iRODS is serving an increasingly important role in data management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mDNS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/mdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/mdns/</guid>
      <description>mDNS resolves host names to IP addresses within small networks that do not include a local name server. It is a zero-configuration service, using essentially the same programming interfaces, packet formats and operating semantics as the unicast Domain Name System (DNS).  Wikipedia     Zeroconf It is a set of technologies that automatically creates a usable computer network based on TCP/IP when computers or network peripherals are interconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thethings.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/thethings-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/thethings-io/</guid>
      <description>thethings.iO is a Wayra Barcelona startup since July 2014 that makes a back-end for Internet of Things. It allows companies to focus more on the product and less on the database and the underlying cloud platform.  crunchbase     Featured In TechCrunch: thethings.iO Pulls In $270k
Forbes: 6 IoT Startups That Make Connecting Things To The Cloud A Breeze
VentureBeat: thethings.iO wants to be the Amazon Web Services for the IoT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>μPnP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/micro-pnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/micro-pnp/</guid>
      <description>A hardware and software solution for plug-and-play integration of embedded peripherals with IoT devices. µPnP provides support for: driver development, automatic integration of third-party peripherals, discovery and remote access to peripheral services.  μPnP     Abstract Internet of Things (IoT) applications require diverse sensors and actuators. However, contemporary IoT devices provide limited support for the integration of third-party peripherals. To tackle this problem, we introduce μPnP: a hardware and software solution for plug-and-play integration of embedded peripherals with IoT devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:30:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/about/</guid>
      <description>The IoT Landscape is a project to explain the various technologies across the Internet of Things. It is an evolving reference guide of IoT technologies started as means of sharing some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my years of working on IoT research at the University of Southampton.
The site is built and updated using the excellent Hugo static site generator, written in Go, and site source code is available on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Pollution</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution sensors are devices that detect and monitor the presence of air pollution of the environment. The majority focuses on components: ozone, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, sulfur dioxide, and nitrous oxide.  Wikipedia     Research Array of Things
 
PM2.5 refers to atmospheric particulate matter (PM) that have a diameter of less than 2.5 micrometers. Such particles are able to bypass the nose and throat and penetrate deep into the lungs and some may even enter the circulatory system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcode</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/barcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/barcode/</guid>
      <description>A barcode is an optical, machine-readable, representation of data; the data usually describes something about the object that carries the barcode. Originally barcodes systematically represented data by varying the widths and spacings of parallel lines.  Wikipedia     Research Industry: Stock Verification
Privacy: Invisible Barcode
Data Glove
 
Example Code 128 is a very high-density barcode symbology. It can encode all 128 characters of ASCII.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beacon</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/beacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/beacon/</guid>
      <description>Beacons are small devices that enable relatively accurate location within a narrow range (like indoors). Beacons periodically transmit small amounts of data within a range of approximately 70 meters, and are often used for indoor location technology.  Wikipedia     Research Smart Wearables Indoor Positioning, Indoor Positioning with Beacons
Health: Navigation for Wheelchair Users, GuideBeacon
 
iBeacon by Apple and Eddystone (formerly UriBeacon) by Google are 2 popular beacon technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EAPs</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/eap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/eap/</guid>
      <description>Electroactive polymers, or EAPs, are polymers that exhibit a change in size or shape when stimulated by an electric field. The most common applications of this type of material are in actuators and sensors. A typical characteristic property of an EAP is that they will undergo a large amount of deformation while sustaining large forces.  Wikipedia     Types  Dielectric
 Ferroelectric polymers
 Electrostrictive graft polymers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECG</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</guid>
      <description>Electrocardiography is the process of recording the electrical activity of the heart over a period of time using electrodes placed on the skin.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Smart Healthcare, Arrhythmia Detection, Low-cost Monitoring, Real-time Monitoring
 
Maker Hackster: RPi+Azure+AD8232, Hackaday: Arduino+ECGShield
 
ECG records the electrical activity generated by heart muscle depolarizations, which propagate in pulsating electrical waves towards the skin. Although the electricity amount is in fact very small, it can be picked up reliably with ECG electrodes attached to the skin (data unit: microvolt, uV).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</guid>
      <description>GPS provides geolocation and time information to a receiver anywhere on or near the Earth. It does not require the user to transmit any data, and it operates independently of any telephonic or internet reception.  Wikipedia     Research Stanford GPS Lab, Supply Chains, Indoor Navigation
 
Alternatives GLONASS is the most developed of the GPS alternatives, and is operated by Russia.
Quora article on alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gyroscope</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</guid>
      <description>A gyroscope is a type of sensor useful for measuring orientation. Electronic, microchip-packaged MEMS gyroscopes are commonly found in consumer electronics devices.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Fall Detection, Hand Tremor
 
Accelerometers Though similar in purpose they measure different things. Gyroscopes determine orientation while accelerometers measure non-gravitational acceleration.
 
Inexpensive vibrating structure microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) gyroscopes have become widely available. These are packaged similarly to other integrated circuits and may provide either analog or digital outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydraulic</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/hydraulic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/hydraulic/</guid>
      <description>A hydraulic actuator consists of cylinder or fluid motor that uses hydraulic power to facilitate mechanical operation. The mechanical motion gives an output in terms of linear, rotatory or oscillatory motion. As liquids are nearly impossible to compress, a hydraulic actuator can exert a large force. The drawback of this approach is its limited acceleration.  Wikipedia     Advantages  Hydraulic actuators are rugged and suited for high-force applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/motor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/motor/</guid>
      <description>An engine or motor is a machine designed to convert one form of energy into mechanical energy. An electric motor is an electrical machine that converts electrical energy into mechanical energy. A stepper motor is a type of DC electric motor.  Wikipedia     Electric Motors Most electric motors operate through the interaction between an electric motor&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field and winding currents to generate force. Electric motors can be powered by direct current (DC) sources, such as from batteries, motor vehicles or rectifiers, or by alternating current (AC) sources, such as from the power grid, inverters or generators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedometer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</guid>
      <description>A pedometer is a device, usually portable and electronic or electromechanical, that counts each step a person takes by detecting the motion of the person&amp;#39;s hands or hips.  Wikipedia     Research Comparing 13 Pedometer Models, Accuracy for Children, How Many Steps Per Day?, Intensity Classification
 
Popular Devices Fitbit, Apple Watch, Nike+, iPod Nano
 
The technology for a pedometer includes a mechanical sensor and software to count steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piezoelectric</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/piezoelectric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/piezoelectric/</guid>
      <description>Piezoelectricity is the electric charge that accumulates in certain solid materials (such as crystals, certain ceramics, and biological matter such as bone, DNA and various proteins) in response to applied mechanical stress. The word piezoelectricity means electricity resulting from pressure and heat. A piezoelectric bimorph is a cantilever used for actuation or sensing which consists of two active layers. One active layer contracts and the other expands if voltage is applied, thus the bimorph bends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pneumatic</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/pneumatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/pneumatic/</guid>
      <description>A pneumatic control valve actuator converts energy (typically in the form of compressed air) into mechanical motion. The motion can be rotary or linear, depending on the type of actuator.  Wikipedia     Types  Tie rod cylinders
 Rotary actuators
 Grippers
 Rodless actuators with magnetic linkage or rotary cylinders
 Rodless actuators with mechanical linkage
 Pneumatic artificial muscles
 Speciality actuators that combine rotary and linear motion—frequently used for clamping operations</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QR Code</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/qrcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/qrcode/</guid>
      <description>QR code is a type of 2D matrix barcode with a machine-readable optical label that contains information about the item to which it is attached. A QR code consists of black squares arranged in a square grid on a white background.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Smart Card, Security for QR Codes
 
Example  
The QR code system became popular due to its fast readability and greater storage capacity compared to standard UPC barcodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</guid>
      <description>Radio-frequency identification (RFID) uses electromagnetic fields to automatically identify and track tags, containing electronically stored information, attached to objects. There are passive and active tags.  Wikipedia     In 2009, Kevin Ashton, who cofounded the Auto-ID Center researching RFID, wrote an article in the RFID Journal titled &amp;ldquo;That &amp;lsquo;Internet of Things&amp;rsquo; Thing&amp;rdquo;. He is attributed with having coined the IoT term then.
 
Frequencies &amp;hellip;    Band Range Speed ~Tag$     LF 10cm Low $1   HF 10cm-1m Low &amp;gt;$0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Servo</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/servo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/servo/</guid>
      <description>In control engineering a servomechanism, sometimes shortened to servo, is an automatic device that uses error-sensing negative feedback to correct the action of a mechanism. It usually includes a built-in encoder or other position feedback mechanism to ensure the output is achieving the desired effect. The term correctly applies only to systems where the feedback or error-correction signals help control mechanical position, speed or other parameters.  Wikipedia     Servomotor A servomotor is a specific type of motor that is combined with a rotary encoder or a potentiometer to form a servomechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/soft/</guid>
      <description>Soft actuators are being developed to handle fragile objects like fruit harvesting in agriculture or manipulating the internal organs in biomedicine that has always been a challenging task for robotics. Unlike conventional actuators, soft actuators produce flexible motion due to the integration of microscopic changes at the molecular level into a macroscopic deformation of the actuator materials.  Wikipedia     PneuNets Bending Actuators PneuNets (pneumatic networks) are a class of soft actuator originally developed by the Whitesides Research Group at Harvard.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Temperature</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/temperature/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/temperature/</guid>
      <description>Temperature sensors are commonly used sensors that detect Temperature or heat.  Wikipedia     Common Types &amp;hellip;  Negative Temperature Coefficient (NTC) thermistor
 Resistance Temperature Detector (RTD)
 Thermocouple
 Semiconductor-based sensors
   
The silicon bandgap temperature sensor is an extremely common form of temperature sensor (thermometer) used in electronic equipment. Its main advantage is that it can be included in a silicon integrated circuit at very low cost.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>