<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Internet of Things Landscape on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Internet of Things Landscape on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:30:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</guid>
      <description>CoAP is a specialised web transfer protocol for use with constrained nodes and constrained (e.g., low-power, lossy) networks.  RFC 7252     Research HTTP/2, CoAP on device HTTP/2 everywhere else, Security, Californium Cloud Services, MQTT vs CoAP, TinyOS Performance, Transport: Logistics
 
CoAP is network-oriented protocol with similar features to HTTP but also allows for low overhead, multicast, etc. CoAP operates over UDP (simpler) instead of TCP compensating for unreliability with a retransmission mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contiki</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/contiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/contiki/</guid>
      <description>An open source operating system for the Internet of Things. Contiki connects tiny low-cost, low-power microcontrollers to the Internet. Contiki is a powerful toolbox for building complex wireless systems.  contiki-os.org     Research vs TinyOS, IoT-Lab Testbed, WSN OS Comparisons
 
Programming on Contiki is done using the Cooja network simulator. To program, control and monitor the remote IoT devices, the back-end C base libraries of RFID chips and sensors can be customised and recompiled to get the desired results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Harvesting</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/energy-harvesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/energy-harvesting/</guid>
      <description>Energy harvesting or scavenging is the process by which ambient energy is derived from external sources, captured, and stored for small, wireless autonomous devices.  Wikipedia     Research Parametric Excitation, Energy Harvesting Technologies Book, Wireless Energy Harvesting, Comparison
 
Makers Solar Harvesting Project, Pieze, Wurth, Energy Harvesting Designs for the IoT
 
All processes that involve energy conversion are, to some degree, inefficient. Motors get hot, as do power transistors, automobile engines, and light bulbs; in each case energy is wasted as heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a publish-subscribe-based lightweight messaging protocol for use on top of TCP/IP. It is designed for connections where a small code footprint is required or the network bandwidth is limited.  Wikipedia     Research CoAP vs MQTT, MQTT and REST, Push Notifications, Secure MQTT
 
MQTT-SN is a variation of the main protocol aimed at embedded devices on non-TCP/IP networks, such as ZigBee. As it does not require the TCP/IP stack, it can be used over a serial link where overhead is really small or over UDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinyOS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/tiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/tiny/</guid>
      <description>TinyOS is an embedded, component-based operating system and platform for low-power wireless devices, such as those used in wireless sensor networks (WSNs), smartdust, ubiquitous computing, personal area networks, building automation, and smart meters.  Wikipedia     Research Original Paper, Hybrid Network Evaluation, Ten-years on Paper
 
Programming on TinyOS is done using a C-like language called nesC. It is a component-based, event-driven programming language with components &amp;ldquo;wired&amp;rdquo; together to run applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Charging</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/wireless-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/wireless-charging/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Charging provides a convenient, safe, and reliable way to charge and power electrical devices, IoT sensors and devices, at home, in the workplace and in industry.  powerbyproxi.com     Research Comparing WiTricity and Inductive Coupling History and Future of Wireless Charging, Transport: Inductive Charging for EVs
 
Although inductive charging with an induction coil is the most common form of wireless charging, uBeam is pioneering an ultrasound method, HumaVox uses near-field radio frequency resonance and WiTricity uses Magnetic Resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Pollution</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution sensors are devices that detect and monitor the presence of air pollution of the environment. The majority focuses on components: ozone, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, sulfur dioxide, and nitrous oxide.  Wikipedia     Research Array of Things
 
PM2.5 refers to atmospheric particulate matter (PM) that have a diameter of less than 2.5 micrometers. Such particles are able to bypass the nose and throat and penetrate deep into the lungs and some may even enter the circulatory system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECG</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</guid>
      <description>Electrocardiography is the process of recording the electrical activity of the heart over a period of time using electrodes placed on the skin.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Smart Healthcare, Arrhythmia Detection, Low-cost Monitoring, Real-time Monitoring
 
Maker Hackster: RPi+Azure+AD8232, Hackaday: Arduino+ECGShield
 
ECG records the electrical activity generated by heart muscle depolarizations, which propagate in pulsating electrical waves towards the skin. Although the electricity amount is in fact very small, it can be picked up reliably with ECG electrodes attached to the skin (data unit: microvolt, uV).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</guid>
      <description>GPS provides geolocation and time information to a receiver anywhere on or near the Earth. It does not require the user to transmit any data, and it operates independently of any telephonic or internet reception.  Wikipedia     Research Stanford GPS Lab, Supply Chains, Indoor Navigation
 
Alternatives GLONASS is the most developed of the GPS alternatives, and is operated by Russia.
Quora article on alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gyroscope</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</guid>
      <description>A gyroscope is a type of sensor useful for measuring orientation. Electronic, microchip-packaged MEMS gyroscopes are commonly found in consumer electronics devices.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Fall Detection, Hand Tremor
 
Accelerometers Though similar in purpose they measure different things. Gyroscopes determine orientation while accelerometers measure non-gravitational acceleration.
 
Inexpensive vibrating structure microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) gyroscopes have become widely available. These are packaged similarly to other integrated circuits and may provide either analog or digital outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedometer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</guid>
      <description>A pedometer is a device, usually portable and electronic or electromechanical, that counts each step a person takes by detecting the motion of the person&amp;#39;s hands or hips.  Wikipedia     Research Comparing 13 Pedometer Models, Accuracy for Children, How Many Steps Per Day?, Intensity Classification
 
Popular Devices Fitbit, Apple Watch, Nike+, iPod Nano
 
The technology for a pedometer includes a mechanical sensor and software to count steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QR Code</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/qrcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/qrcode/</guid>
      <description>QR code is a type of 2D matrix barcode with a machine-readable optical label that contains information about the item to which it is attached. A QR code consists of black squares arranged in a square grid on a white background.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Smart Card, Security for QR Codes
 
Example  
The QR code system became popular due to its fast readability and greater storage capacity compared to standard UPC barcodes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>