<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Internet of Things Landscape on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Internet of Things Landscape on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:30:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/arduino/</guid>
      <description>Arduino is an open source single-board microcontroller for building digital devices and interactive objects that can sense and control objects in the physical world. Arduino boards are available commercially in preassembled form, or as do-it-yourself kits.  Wikipedia     Research Agriculture: Soil Moisture Monitoring
Smart City/Smart Home: Smart Garbage, $30 Home Automation System, Environmental Monitoring
Industry: Smart Supply Chain
 
Series Comparison &amp;hellip;    Arduino CPU SRAM Flash     Yún 400 MHz 64 MB 16 MB   Uno 16 MHz 2 KB 32 KB   101 32 MHz 24 KB 196 KB   Micro 16 MHz 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microbit</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/microbit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/microbit/</guid>
      <description>The BBC Micro Bit is an ARM-based embedded system designed by the BBC for use in computer education. The board is 4 cm × 5 cm and has an ARM Cortex-M0 processor, accelerometer and magnetometer sensors, Bluetooth and USB connectivity, a display consisting of 25 LEDs, two programmable buttons, and can be powered by either USB or an external battery pack.  Wikipedia     Hardware  Size: 43 mm × 52 mm (half credit card)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPi</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/rpi/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/rpi/</guid>
      <description>The Raspberry Pi is a series of popular small and low-cost single-board computers. It was first developed in the UK by the Raspberry Pi Foundation. Manifold products have been created to accompany, modify, and enhance the Pi’s capabilities.  Wikipedia     Research Health Monitoring, Web of Things Book, Industrial Automation, Environmental Monitoring
 
Series Comparison    RPi CPU RAM WiFi     3 4 x 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1888.3</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/18883-green-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/18883-green-security/</guid>
      <description>Green Security is a new research field defining and investigating security solutions under an energy-aware perspective. 1888.3 describes the enhanced security management function for the IEEE 1888 &amp;#39;Ubiquitous Green Community Control Network Protocol&amp;#39;.  IEEE     Research Smart meter, Efficient Power Grid Algorithms, Proxy, Survey on Protocols and Standards, Real-time Smart Grid
 
Ubiquitous computing (or &amp;ldquo;ubicomp&amp;rdquo;) is a concept in software engineering and computer science where computing is made to appear anytime and everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANT&#43;</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</guid>
      <description>ANT&amp;#43; is a wireless protocol for monitoring sensor data such as a person&amp;#39;s heart rate or a car&amp;#39;s tyre/tire pressure, as well as the control of systems like indoor lighting or a television set.  Wikipedia     
 
ANT is a practical wireless sensor network protocol running in the 2.4 GHz ISM band. Designed for ultra-low power, ease of use, efficiency and scalability, ANT easily handles peer-to-peer, star, connected star, tree and fixed mesh topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android Things</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/android-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/android-things/</guid>
      <description>Android Things (codenamed/rebranded from Brillo) is an Android-based embedded operating system platform by Google. It is aimed to be used with low-power and memory constrained Internet of Things (IoT) devices, which are usually built from different microcontroller platforms.  Wikipedia     Like updates for Android Phones, developers can push Google-provided OS updates and custom app updates using the same over-the-air infrastructure that Google uses for its products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beagle</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/beagle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/beagle/</guid>
      <description>Beagles are low-cost, fan-less single-board computers based on low-power Texas Instruments processors featuring the ARM Cortex-A series core with all of the expandability of today&amp;#39;s desktop machines, but without the bulk, expense, or noise. Initially, development was targeted at enabling Linux distributions to improve support for ARM devices.  BeagleBoard.org     BeagleBone VS BeagleBone Black 
 elinux.org    
BeagleBoard The USB-powered BeagleBoard is a low-cost, fan-less single board computer that unleashes laptop-like performance and expandability without the bulk, expense, or noise of typical desktop machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth is a wireless technology standard for exchanging data over short distances (using short-wavelength UHF radio waves in the industrial, scientific and medical (ISM) radio bands from 2.4 to 2.485 GHz) from fixed and mobile devices, and building personal area networks (PANs). Bluetooth Low Energy or Smart is intended to provide considerably reduced power consumption and cost while maintaining a similar communication range.  Wikipedia     Feature Compare &amp;hellip;    Feature BT-LE BT     Audio/Headset No Yes   Data Yes Yes   A/V Control Non-Native Native   Throughput Low Medium   Authentication No For Non-Audio Only</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOx</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cisco-iox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cisco-iox/</guid>
      <description>IOx combines IoT application execution within the fog and offers highly secure connectivity with Cisco IOS technology, as well as powerful services for rapid, reliable integration with IoT sensors and the cloud.  cisco.com     Architecture 
 cisco.com    
The Cisco IOx application environment combines IoT application execution within the fog; secure connectivity with Cisco IOS Software; and powerful services for rapid, reliable integration with Internet of Things (IoT) sensors and the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</guid>
      <description>CoAP is a specialised web transfer protocol for use with constrained nodes and constrained (e.g., low-power, lossy) networks.  RFC 7252     Research HTTP/2, CoAP on device HTTP/2 everywhere else, Security, Californium Cloud Services, MQTT vs CoAP, TinyOS Performance, Transport: Logistics
 
CoAP is network-oriented protocol with similar features to HTTP but also allows for low overhead, multicast, etc. CoAP operates over UDP (simpler) instead of TCP compensating for unreliability with a retransmission mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computes.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/computes-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/computes-io/</guid>
      <description>Computes.io is a mesh networked, distributed supercomputing platform powered by IPFS. Each node on the mesh network acts as both a core and kernel, meaning that each node can perform computations for other machines as well as request computations from itself and other machines.  computes.io     Computes.io is a distributed supercomputer mesh network. Each node on the mesh network acts as both a core and kernel — meaning that each node can perform Javascript computations for other machines as well as request computations from itself and other machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contiki</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/contiki/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/contiki/</guid>
      <description>An open source operating system for the Internet of Things. Contiki connects tiny low-cost, low-power microcontrollers to the Internet. Contiki is a powerful toolbox for building complex wireless systems.  contiki-os.org     Research vs TinyOS, IoT-Lab Testbed, WSN OS Comparisons
 
Programming on Contiki is done using the Cooja network simulator. To program, control and monitor the remote IoT devices, the back-end C base libraries of RFID chips and sensors can be customised and recompiled to get the desired results.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CubieBoard</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/cubieboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/cubieboard/</guid>
      <description>Cubieboard is a single-board computer which can run Android 4 ICS, Ubuntu 12.04 desktop, Fedora 19 ARM Remix desktop, Arch Linux ARM, a Debian-based Cubian distribution, or OpenBSD. It uses the AllWinner A10 SoC, popular on cheap tablets, phones and media PCs. This SoC is used by developers of the lima driver, an open-source driver for the ARM Mali GPU.  Wikipedia     Cubietruck Plus (Cubieboard 5) Hardware (More Models)  SoC: Allwinner H8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS-SD</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/dns-sd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/dns-sd/</guid>
      <description>DNS-SD allows clients to discover a named list of service instances, given a service type, and to resolve those services to hostnames using standard DNS queries. The specification is compatible with existing unicast DNS server and client software, but works equally well with Multicast DNS in a zero-configuration environment.  Wikipedia     Zeroconf It is a set of technologies that automatically creates a usable computer network based on TCP/IP when computers or network peripherals are interconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Harvesting</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/energy-harvesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/energy-harvesting/</guid>
      <description>Energy harvesting or scavenging is the process by which ambient energy is derived from external sources, captured, and stored for small, wireless autonomous devices.  Wikipedia     Research Parametric Excitation, Energy Harvesting Technologies Book, Wireless Energy Harvesting, Comparison
 
Makers Solar Harvesting Project, Pieze, Wurth, Energy Harvesting Designs for the IoT
 
All processes that involve energy conversion are, to some degree, inefficient. Motors get hot, as do power transistors, automobile engines, and light bulbs; in each case energy is wasted as heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eywa</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Eywa is an interoperable fog computing infrastructure for RDF Stream Processing (RSP). It implements a means of distribution and control of query workload for stream processing on flexible, interopeable, RDF graph structures.  eugenesiow.com     Paper Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gadgeteer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gadgeteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gadgeteer/</guid>
      <description>Microsoft .NET Gadgeteer is an open-source rapid-prototyping standard for building small electronic devices using the Microsoft .NET Micro Framework and Microsoft Visual Studio/Visual C# Express. The Gadgeteer platform centers around a Gadgeteer mainboard with a microcontroller running the .NET Micro Framework.  Wikipedia     .NET Gadgeteer was created by researchers at Microsoft as an internal prototyping tool, but because of external interest, particualrly from educators and hobbyists, we turned it into open source software which now has a vibrant hardware ecosystem from multiple manufacturers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Galileo</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/galileo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/galileo/</guid>
      <description>Intel Galileo is the first in a line of Arduino-certified development boards based on Intel x86 architecture and is designed for the maker and education communities. Intel released two versions of Galileo, referred to as Gen 1 and Gen 2. These development boards are sometimes called &amp;#39;Breakout boards&amp;#39;.  Wikipedia     Intel Galileo combines Intel technology with support for Arduino ready-made hardware expansion cards (called &amp;ldquo;shields&amp;rdquo;) and the Arduino software development environment and libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gizmo2</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gizmo2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gizmo2/</guid>
      <description>Gizmo2 is the second generation open source x86 development board from GizmoSphere. Gizmo 2 provides the power of a high performance computer and the I/O capabilities of a microcontroller through the use of an AMD Embedded G-Series System-on-Chip (SOC). The board includes the AMD GX-210HA dual-core processor, combined on a single die with AMD Radeon HD 8210E discrete-class graphics, providing 85 GFLOPS performance while drawing only 9 watts TDP.  element14     The new Gizmo 2 platform is the second-generation x86-based DIY single-board-computer (SBC) from Gizmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/http2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/http2/</guid>
      <description>HTTP/2 is a major revision of the HTTP network protocol used by the World Wide Web and derived from Google&amp;#39;s earlier experimental SPDY protocol.  Wikipedia     Research HTTP/1.1 pipelining vs HTTP2 in-the-clear, HTTP/2 multiplexed stream, HTTP/2 in Web Services
 
HTTP/2 Server Push allows you to send site assets to the user before they’ve even asked for them. It’s an elegant way to achieve the performance benefits of HTTP/1 optimization practices such as inlining, but without the drawbacks that come with that practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/ipfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/ipfs/</guid>
      <description>InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a protocol designed to create a permanent and decentralized method of storing and sharing files. It is a content-addressable, peer-to-peer hypermedia distribution protocol. Nodes in the IPFS network form a distributed file system.  Wikipedia     IPNS IPFS has a name service called IPNS, a global namespace based on PKI, serves to build trust chains, is compatible with other NSes and can map DNS, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPsec</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/lora/</guid>
      <description>IPsec is a network protocol suite that authenticates and encrypts the packets of data sent over a network. IPsec includes protocols for establishing mutual authentication between agents at the beginning of the session and negotiation of cryptographic keys to use during the session.  Wikipedia     Specifications RFC 4301 defines a Security Architecture for the Internet Protocol, while RFC 4303 defines the Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) protocol and RFC 4309 describes the use of Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) in Counter with CBC-MAC (CCM) Mode as an IPsec Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LTE</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lte/</guid>
      <description>LTE is a standard for high-speed wireless communication for mobile devices and data terminals, based on the GSM/EDGE and UMTS/HSPA technologies. It increases the capacity and speed using a different radio interface together with core network improvements. The standard is developed by the 3GPP (3rd Generation Partnership Project).  Wikipedia     NB-IoT &amp;hellip; NarrowBand IoT (NB-IoT) is a Low Power Wide Area Network (LPWAN) radio technology standard. NB-IoT focuses specifically on indoor coverage, low cost, long battery life, and enabling a large number of connected devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LiteOS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/lite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/lite/</guid>
      <description>LiteOS is a Unix-like operating system that fits on memory-constrained sensor nodes. LiteOS provides a familiar programming environment based on Unix, threads, and C. It follows a hybrid programming model that allows both event-driven and thread-driven programming.  Wikipedia     Research Original LiteOS Paper, Interactive UNIX Shell Demo Paper, Event Traces in the LiteOS
 
Huawei also developed an open-source operating system for the IoT called Huawei LiteOS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRaWAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lora/</guid>
      <description>LoRaWAN is a Low Power Wide Area Network (LPWAN) specification intended for wireless battery operated Things in a regional, national or global network. It is designed to allow low-powered devices to communicate with Internet-connected applications over long range wireless connections.  lora-alliance.org     The Things Network The Things Network is a first-of-its-kind system that uses low-power, low-bandwidth LoRaWAN technology to cover the city with a wireless signal that allows objects like boats, trash cans and street lights to become tools for developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a publish-subscribe-based lightweight messaging protocol for use on top of TCP/IP. It is designed for connections where a small code footprint is required or the network bandwidth is limited.  Wikipedia     Research CoAP vs MQTT, MQTT and REST, Push Notifications, Secure MQTT
 
MQTT-SN is a variation of the main protocol aimed at embedded devices on non-TCP/IP networks, such as ZigBee. As it does not require the TCP/IP stack, it can be used over a serial link where overhead is really small or over UDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motion Charging</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/motion-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/motion-charging/</guid>
      <description>Motion-powered charging involves the transformation of naturally occurring motion in the form of kinetic energy into electricity which can be used to charge batteries and power electronic devices.   Research Copenhagen Wheel, Vint Cerf&amp;rsquo;s Taking the Internet to the Next Physical Level, Self-charging Textile
 
Ampy Move is a wearable motion-charger that transforms the kinetic energy from motion into power for smartphone and wearables. Inductors in the Move device transform movement into usable power to charge devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NUC</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/nuc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/nuc/</guid>
      <description>Next Unit of Computing (NUC) is a small-form-factor personal computer designed by Intel. Its motherboard measures 4 × 4 inches (10.16 × 10.16 cm). The barebone kits consist of the board, in a plastic case with a fan, an external power supply and VESA mounting plate.  Wikipedia     Seventh Generation Intel&amp;rsquo;s seventh generation NUC models, codenamed Baby Canyon, are based on their Kaby Lake-U processors with a TDP from 15 W to 28 W.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIOTRe</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/piotre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/piotre/</guid>
      <description>PIOTRe is a Personal IoT Repository that allows applications to be built on interoperable and efficient semantic database technology for deployment on lightweight IoT devices. The name PIOTRe is derived from the name Peter meaning &amp;#39;stone&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;rock&amp;#39; and is the foundation for personal IoT device repositories.  cisco.com     Architecture 
 cisco.com    
PIOTRe PIOTRe is a Personal IoT Repository based on sparql2sql, sparql2stream and sparql2fed technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phidgets</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/phidgets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/phidgets/</guid>
      <description>Phidgets are a system of low-cost electronic components and sensors that are controlled by a personal computer. Using the Universal Serial Bus (USB) as the basis for all phidgets, the complexity is managed behind an Application Programming Interface (API). A phidget is a physical representation or implementation of a GUI widget.  Wikipedia     Phidgets are an easy to use set of building blocks for low cost sensing and control from your PC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resin.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/resin-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/resin-io/</guid>
      <description>Resin.io offers a development and deployment framework based upon Linux and containers that is designed to facilitate control of the on-device environment, provision devices on the network, and manage a fleet of systems.  resin.io     The Good  Developer friendly: iterate and push
 20 supported maker devices
 Container-based
 Open Source: ResinOS, Balena
 First 10 devices free
   
   Features &amp;hellip;     Control on-device environment   Provision devices easily   Manage device fleet at scale   Automate device fleet from own cloud   Encrypted communication   Continuous updates</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SensorCloud</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/sensorcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/sensorcloud/</guid>
      <description>SensorCloud is a sensor data storage, visualization and remote management platform. It is a product of LORD MicroStrain Sensing Systems and leverages Cloud computing technologies to provide data scalability, rapid visualization, and user programmable analysis.  sensorcloud.com     MathEngine A $50/month per SensorCloud account account. It provides multiple ways to analyze data. It can generate FFT plots, filter out frequencies, and smooth out noisy data. It also integrates IPython Notebooks into its cloud service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SmartThings</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/smartthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/smartthings/</guid>
      <description>The SmartThings Hub acts as the centre of a smart home. Able to connect wirelessly with hundreds of compatible smart devices, allowing monitoring, controlling and securing a home from anywhere.  samsung.com     SmartThings primary products include a free SmartThings app, a SmartThings Hub, as well as various sensors and smart devices. The SmartThings native mobile application allows users to control, automate, and monitor their home environment via mobile device.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/solid/</guid>
      <description>Solid (derived from &amp;#39;social linked data&amp;#39;) is a proposed set of conventions and tools for building decentralized social applications based on Linked Data principles. The project aims to radically change the way Web applications work today, resulting in true data ownership as well as improved privacy.  computes.io     Apps  Plume Blogging
 Cimba Microblogging
 Contacts
 Dokieli Article Publishing
 Profile Editing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinkerBoard</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/tinkerboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/tinkerboard/</guid>
      <description>The ASUS Tinker Board is a single board computer launched by ASUS in early 2017. Its physical size and GPIO pinout are designed to be compatible with the second-generation and later Raspberry Pi models. The first released board features 4K video, 2GB of onboard RAM, gigabit Ethernet and a Rockchip RK3288 processor running at 1.8 GHz.  Wikipedia     Tinker Board is a Single Board Computer (SBC) in an ultra-small form factor that offers class-leading performance while leveraging outstanding mechanical compatibility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TinyOS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/tiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/tiny/</guid>
      <description>TinyOS is an embedded, component-based operating system and platform for low-power wireless devices, such as those used in wireless sensor networks (WSNs), smartdust, ubiquitous computing, personal area networks, building automation, and smart meters.  Wikipedia     Research Original Paper, Hybrid Network Evaluation, Ten-years on Paper
 
Programming on TinyOS is done using a C-like language called nesC. It is a component-based, event-driven programming language with components &amp;ldquo;wired&amp;rdquo; together to run applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiMAX</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wimax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wimax/</guid>
      <description>WiMAX is a family of wireless communication standards based on the IEEE 802.16 set of standards, which provide multiple physical layer (PHY) and Media Access Control (MAC) options. It can enable wireless usage at long distances.  Wikipedia     Possible Uses  Portable mobile broadband connectivity across cities
 Wireless alternative to cable and DSL for &amp;ldquo;last mile&amp;rdquo; broadband
 Data, telecommunications (VoIP) and IPTV services (triple play)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wireless Charging</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/power/wireless-charging/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/power/wireless-charging/</guid>
      <description>Wireless Charging provides a convenient, safe, and reliable way to charge and power electrical devices, IoT sensors and devices, at home, in the workplace and in industry.  powerbyproxi.com     Research Comparing WiTricity and Inductive Coupling History and Future of Wireless Charging, Transport: Inductive Charging for EVs
 
Although inductive charging with an induction coil is the most common form of wireless charging, uBeam is pioneering an ultrasound method, HumaVox uses near-field radio frequency resonance and WiTricity uses Magnetic Resonance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMPP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</guid>
      <description>XMPP is a communications protocol for message-oriented middleware based on XML. It enables the near-real-time exchange of structured yet extensible data between any two or more network entities.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Lightweight IoT Pub/Sub, SmartObjects with mDNS, Cryptographic Hashes
 
XMPP supports different communication patterns, such as Request/Response, Asynchronous Messaging, Publish/Subscribe, Event subscription (Observe) and Delayed delivery. XMPP also has support for different Quality of Service levels for messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xively</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/xively/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/xively/</guid>
      <description>Xively offers an Internet of Things (IoT) platform as a service, business services, and partners that enable businesses to quickly connect products and operations to the Internet. It is a division of LogMeIn Inc.  Wikipedia     Customers Agriculture: Freight Farms, Smart Home: Halo Smart Labs, Lutron, Watts, SureFlap, Industry: Sato, New England Biolabs
 
   Features     Device Management   Identity Management   Device and Cloud Security   Integrations with Enterprise Systems   Remote Device Support</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zigbee</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</guid>
      <description>Zigbee is an IEEE 802.15.4-based specification for a suite of high-level communication protocols used to create personal area networks with small, low-power digital radios, such as for home automation, medical device data collection, and other low-power low-bandwidth needs, designed for small scale projects which need wireless connection.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.15.4 IEEE 802.15.4 is a technical standard which defines the operation of low-rate wireless personal area networks (LR-WPANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mDNS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/mdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/mdns/</guid>
      <description>mDNS resolves host names to IP addresses within small networks that do not include a local name server. It is a zero-configuration service, using essentially the same programming interfaces, packet formats and operating semantics as the unicast Domain Name System (DNS).  Wikipedia     Zeroconf It is a set of technologies that automatically creates a usable computer network based on TCP/IP when computers or network peripherals are interconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thethings.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/thethings-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/thethings-io/</guid>
      <description>thethings.iO is a Wayra Barcelona startup since July 2014 that makes a back-end for Internet of Things. It allows companies to focus more on the product and less on the database and the underlying cloud platform.  crunchbase     Featured In TechCrunch: thethings.iO Pulls In $270k
Forbes: 6 IoT Startups That Make Connecting Things To The Cloud A Breeze
VentureBeat: thethings.iO wants to be the Amazon Web Services for the IoT</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:30:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/about/</guid>
      <description>The IoT Landscape is a project to explain the various technologies across the Internet of Things. It is an evolving reference guide of IoT technologies started as means of sharing some of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned in my years of working on IoT research at the University of Southampton.
The site is built and updated using the excellent Hugo static site generator, written in Go, and site source code is available on Github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Air Pollution</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/air-pollution/</guid>
      <description>Air pollution sensors are devices that detect and monitor the presence of air pollution of the environment. The majority focuses on components: ozone, particulate matter, carbon monoxide, sulfur dioxide, and nitrous oxide.  Wikipedia     Research Array of Things
 
PM2.5 refers to atmospheric particulate matter (PM) that have a diameter of less than 2.5 micrometers. Such particles are able to bypass the nose and throat and penetrate deep into the lungs and some may even enter the circulatory system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barcode</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/barcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/barcode/</guid>
      <description>A barcode is an optical, machine-readable, representation of data; the data usually describes something about the object that carries the barcode. Originally barcodes systematically represented data by varying the widths and spacings of parallel lines.  Wikipedia     Research Industry: Stock Verification
Privacy: Invisible Barcode
Data Glove
 
Example Code 128 is a very high-density barcode symbology. It can encode all 128 characters of ASCII.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beacon</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/beacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/beacon/</guid>
      <description>Beacons are small devices that enable relatively accurate location within a narrow range (like indoors). Beacons periodically transmit small amounts of data within a range of approximately 70 meters, and are often used for indoor location technology.  Wikipedia     Research Smart Wearables Indoor Positioning, Indoor Positioning with Beacons
Health: Navigation for Wheelchair Users, GuideBeacon
 
iBeacon by Apple and Eddystone (formerly UriBeacon) by Google are 2 popular beacon technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ECG</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/ecg/</guid>
      <description>Electrocardiography is the process of recording the electrical activity of the heart over a period of time using electrodes placed on the skin.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Smart Healthcare, Arrhythmia Detection, Low-cost Monitoring, Real-time Monitoring
 
Maker Hackster: RPi+Azure+AD8232, Hackaday: Arduino+ECGShield
 
ECG records the electrical activity generated by heart muscle depolarizations, which propagate in pulsating electrical waves towards the skin. Although the electricity amount is in fact very small, it can be picked up reliably with ECG electrodes attached to the skin (data unit: microvolt, uV).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</guid>
      <description>GPS provides geolocation and time information to a receiver anywhere on or near the Earth. It does not require the user to transmit any data, and it operates independently of any telephonic or internet reception.  Wikipedia     Research Stanford GPS Lab, Supply Chains, Indoor Navigation
 
Alternatives GLONASS is the most developed of the GPS alternatives, and is operated by Russia.
Quora article on alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gyroscope</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</guid>
      <description>A gyroscope is a type of sensor useful for measuring orientation. Electronic, microchip-packaged MEMS gyroscopes are commonly found in consumer electronics devices.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Fall Detection, Hand Tremor
 
Accelerometers Though similar in purpose they measure different things. Gyroscopes determine orientation while accelerometers measure non-gravitational acceleration.
 
Inexpensive vibrating structure microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) gyroscopes have become widely available. These are packaged similarly to other integrated circuits and may provide either analog or digital outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedometer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</guid>
      <description>A pedometer is a device, usually portable and electronic or electromechanical, that counts each step a person takes by detecting the motion of the person&amp;#39;s hands or hips.  Wikipedia     Research Comparing 13 Pedometer Models, Accuracy for Children, How Many Steps Per Day?, Intensity Classification
 
Popular Devices Fitbit, Apple Watch, Nike+, iPod Nano
 
The technology for a pedometer includes a mechanical sensor and software to count steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QR Code</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/qrcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/qrcode/</guid>
      <description>QR code is a type of 2D matrix barcode with a machine-readable optical label that contains information about the item to which it is attached. A QR code consists of black squares arranged in a square grid on a white background.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Smart Card, Security for QR Codes
 
Example  
The QR code system became popular due to its fast readability and greater storage capacity compared to standard UPC barcodes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</guid>
      <description>Radio-frequency identification (RFID) uses electromagnetic fields to automatically identify and track tags, containing electronically stored information, attached to objects. There are passive and active tags.  Wikipedia     In 2009, Kevin Ashton, who cofounded the Auto-ID Center researching RFID, wrote an article in the RFID Journal titled &amp;ldquo;That &amp;lsquo;Internet of Things&amp;rsquo; Thing&amp;rdquo;. He is attributed with having coined the IoT term then.
 
Frequencies &amp;hellip;    Band Range Speed ~Tag$     LF 10cm Low $1   HF 10cm-1m Low &amp;gt;$0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>