<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Protocol on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/protocol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Protocol on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/protocol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>1888.3</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/18883-green-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/18883-green-security/</guid>
      <description>Green Security is a new research field defining and investigating security solutions under an energy-aware perspective. 1888.3 describes the enhanced security management function for the IEEE 1888 &amp;#39;Ubiquitous Green Community Control Network Protocol&amp;#39;.  IEEE     Research Smart meter, Efficient Power Grid Algorithms, Proxy, Survey on Protocols and Standards, Real-time Smart Grid
 
Ubiquitous computing (or &amp;ldquo;ubicomp&amp;rdquo;) is a concept in software engineering and computer science where computing is made to appear anytime and everywhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANT&#43;</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</guid>
      <description>ANT&amp;#43; is a wireless protocol for monitoring sensor data such as a person&amp;#39;s heart rate or a car&amp;#39;s tyre/tire pressure, as well as the control of systems like indoor lighting or a television set.  Wikipedia     
 
ANT is a practical wireless sensor network protocol running in the 2.4 GHz ISM band. Designed for ultra-low power, ease of use, efficiency and scalability, ANT easily handles peer-to-peer, star, connected star, tree and fixed mesh topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth is a wireless technology standard for exchanging data over short distances (using short-wavelength UHF radio waves in the industrial, scientific and medical (ISM) radio bands from 2.4 to 2.485 GHz) from fixed and mobile devices, and building personal area networks (PANs). Bluetooth Low Energy or Smart is intended to provide considerably reduced power consumption and cost while maintaining a similar communication range.  Wikipedia     Feature Compare &amp;hellip;    Feature BT-LE BT     Audio/Headset No Yes   Data Yes Yes   A/V Control Non-Native Native   Throughput Low Medium   Authentication No For Non-Audio Only</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</guid>
      <description>CoAP is a specialised web transfer protocol for use with constrained nodes and constrained (e.g., low-power, lossy) networks.  RFC 7252     Research HTTP/2, CoAP on device HTTP/2 everywhere else, Security, Californium Cloud Services, MQTT vs CoAP, TinyOS Performance, Transport: Logistics
 
CoAP is network-oriented protocol with similar features to HTTP but also allows for low overhead, multicast, etc. CoAP operates over UDP (simpler) instead of TCP compensating for unreliability with a retransmission mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DNS-SD</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/dns-sd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/dns-sd/</guid>
      <description>DNS-SD allows clients to discover a named list of service instances, given a service type, and to resolve those services to hostnames using standard DNS queries. The specification is compatible with existing unicast DNS server and client software, but works equally well with Multicast DNS in a zero-configuration environment.  Wikipedia     Zeroconf It is a set of technologies that automatically creates a usable computer network based on TCP/IP when computers or network peripherals are interconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/http2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/http2/</guid>
      <description>HTTP/2 is a major revision of the HTTP network protocol used by the World Wide Web and derived from Google&amp;#39;s earlier experimental SPDY protocol.  Wikipedia     Research HTTP/1.1 pipelining vs HTTP2 in-the-clear, HTTP/2 multiplexed stream, HTTP/2 in Web Services
 
HTTP/2 Server Push allows you to send site assets to the user before they’ve even asked for them. It’s an elegant way to achieve the performance benefits of HTTP/1 optimization practices such as inlining, but without the drawbacks that come with that practice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPsec</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/ipsec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/ipsec/</guid>
      <description>IPsec is a network protocol suite that authenticates and encrypts the packets of data sent over a network. IPsec includes protocols for establishing mutual authentication between agents at the beginning of the session and negotiation of cryptographic keys to use during the session.  Wikipedia     Specifications RFC 4301 defines a Security Architecture for the Internet Protocol, while RFC 4303 defines the Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) protocol and RFC 4309 describes the use of Advanced Encryption Standard (AES) in Counter with CBC-MAC (CCM) Mode as an IPsec Encapsulating Security Payload (ESP) mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LTE</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lte/</guid>
      <description>LTE is a standard for high-speed wireless communication for mobile devices and data terminals, based on the GSM/EDGE and UMTS/HSPA technologies. It increases the capacity and speed using a different radio interface together with core network improvements. The standard is developed by the 3GPP (3rd Generation Partnership Project).  Wikipedia     NB-IoT &amp;hellip; NarrowBand IoT (NB-IoT) is a Low Power Wide Area Network (LPWAN) radio technology standard. NB-IoT focuses specifically on indoor coverage, low cost, long battery life, and enabling a large number of connected devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LoRaWAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lora/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/lora/</guid>
      <description>LoRaWAN is a Low Power Wide Area Network (LPWAN) specification intended for wireless battery operated Things in a regional, national or global network. It is designed to allow low-powered devices to communicate with Internet-connected applications over long range wireless connections.  lora-alliance.org     The Things Network The Things Network is a first-of-its-kind system that uses low-power, low-bandwidth LoRaWAN technology to cover the city with a wireless signal that allows objects like boats, trash cans and street lights to become tools for developers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a publish-subscribe-based lightweight messaging protocol for use on top of TCP/IP. It is designed for connections where a small code footprint is required or the network bandwidth is limited.  Wikipedia     Research CoAP vs MQTT, MQTT and REST, Push Notifications, Secure MQTT
 
MQTT-SN is a variation of the main protocol aimed at embedded devices on non-TCP/IP networks, such as ZigBee. As it does not require the TCP/IP stack, it can be used over a serial link where overhead is really small or over UDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multicast CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/multicast-coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/multicast-coap/</guid>
      <description>Group communication involves a one-to-many relationship between CoAP endpoints. Specifically, a single CoAP client can simultaneously get (or set) resources from multiple CoAP servers using CoAP over IP multicast. CoAP is a web transfer protocol based on Representational State Transfer (REST) for resource constrained devices operating in an IP network.  RFC 7390     In M2M applications, for example, home or building automation, there is a need for local clients and servers to find and interact with each other without human intervention.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSDP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/ssdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/ssdp/</guid>
      <description>The Simple Service Discovery Protocol (SSDP) is a network protocol based on the Internet Protocol Suite for advertisement and discovery of network services and presence information. It accomplishes this without assistance of server-based configuration mechanisms, such as the Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) or the Domain Name System (DNS), and without special static configuration of a network host.  Wikipedia     The Simple Service Discovery Protocol (SSDP) provides a mechanism where by network clients, with little or no static configuration, can discover network services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Threat Defence</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/security/threat-defence/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/security/threat-defence/</guid>
      <description>IoT Threat Defense securely segments IoT devices based on policy that provides an adaptable, extensible means of protecting vital services at IoT scale. It also provides a cybersecurity architecture, featuring a strong cast of integrated products from Identity Services Engine (ISE) and TrustSec to Stealthwatch and Next-Generation Firewall.  cisco.com     IoT Threat Defence works through…  Segmentation
 Secure remote access
 Security services
 Visibility and analysis</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPnP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/upnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/upnp/</guid>
      <description>Universal Plug and Play (UPnP) is a set of networking protocols that permits networked devices, such as personal computers, printers, Internet gateways, Wi-Fi access points and mobile devices to seamlessly discover each other&amp;#39;s presence on the network and establish functional network services for data sharing, communications, and entertainment.  Wikipedia     Protocol UPnP assumes the network must run Internet Protocol (IP) and then leverages HTTP, SOAP and XML on top of IP, in order to provide device/service description, actions, data transfer and eventing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WiMAX</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wimax/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/gateway-network/wimax/</guid>
      <description>WiMAX is a family of wireless communication standards based on the IEEE 802.16 set of standards, which provide multiple physical layer (PHY) and Media Access Control (MAC) options. It can enable wireless usage at long distances.  Wikipedia     Possible Uses  Portable mobile broadband connectivity across cities
 Wireless alternative to cable and DSL for &amp;ldquo;last mile&amp;rdquo; broadband
 Data, telecommunications (VoIP) and IPTV services (triple play)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMPP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</guid>
      <description>XMPP is a communications protocol for message-oriented middleware based on XML. It enables the near-real-time exchange of structured yet extensible data between any two or more network entities.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Lightweight IoT Pub/Sub, SmartObjects with mDNS, Cryptographic Hashes
 
XMPP supports different communication patterns, such as Request/Response, Asynchronous Messaging, Publish/Subscribe, Event subscription (Observe) and Delayed delivery. XMPP also has support for different Quality of Service levels for messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zigbee</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</guid>
      <description>Zigbee is an IEEE 802.15.4-based specification for a suite of high-level communication protocols used to create personal area networks with small, low-power digital radios, such as for home automation, medical device data collection, and other low-power low-bandwidth needs, designed for small scale projects which need wireless connection.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.15.4 IEEE 802.15.4 is a technical standard which defines the operation of low-rate wireless personal area networks (LR-WPANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>mDNS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/mdns/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/mdns/</guid>
      <description>mDNS resolves host names to IP addresses within small networks that do not include a local name server. It is a zero-configuration service, using essentially the same programming interfaces, packet formats and operating semantics as the unicast Domain Name System (DNS).  Wikipedia     Zeroconf It is a set of technologies that automatically creates a usable computer network based on TCP/IP when computers or network peripherals are interconnected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>μPnP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/micro-pnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/micro-pnp/</guid>
      <description>A hardware and software solution for plug-and-play integration of embedded peripherals with IoT devices. µPnP provides support for: driver development, automatic integration of third-party peripherals, discovery and remote access to peripheral services.  μPnP     Abstract Internet of Things (IoT) applications require diverse sensors and actuators. However, contemporary IoT devices provide limited support for the integration of third-party peripherals. To tackle this problem, we introduce μPnP: a hardware and software solution for plug-and-play integration of embedded peripherals with IoT devices.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>