<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Distributed on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/distributed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Distributed on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/distributed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ANGELS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/angels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/angels/</guid>
      <description>ANGELS is a work in progress research project that explores the idea of utilising smart edge devices for performing certain portions of the data analysis tasks in IoT.  Wikipedia     Abstract The current global emphasis on “Internet of Things (IoT)” have highlighted the extreme importance of sensor-based intelligent and ubiquitous systems which are more commonly known as “cyber-physical systems.” The technology has the potential to create a network of smart devices and things to an extent that has never been envisaged before, far outnumbering the number of devices connected in the Internet as we know today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/ceph/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/ceph/</guid>
      <description>Ceph is a free-software storage platform that implements object storage on a single distributed computer cluster, and provides interfaces for object-, block- and file-level storage. Ceph aims primarily for completely distributed operation without a single point of failure, scalable to the exabyte level, and freely available. As a result of its design, the system is both self-healing and self-managing, aiming to minimize administration time and other costs.  Wikipedia         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cisco IOx</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cisco-iox/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cisco-iox/</guid>
      <description>IOx combines IoT application execution within the fog and offers highly secure connectivity with Cisco IOS technology, as well as powerful services for rapid, reliable integration with IoT sensors and the cloud.  cisco.com     Architecture 
 cisco.com    
The Cisco IOx application environment combines IoT application execution within the fog; secure connectivity with Cisco IOS Software; and powerful services for rapid, reliable integration with Internet of Things (IoT) sensors and the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudlet</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cloudlet/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/cloudlet/</guid>
      <description>A cloudlet is a mobility-enhanced small-scale cloud datacenter that is located at the edge of the Internet. The main purpose of the cloudlet is supporting resource-intensive and interactive mobile applications by providing powerful computing resources to mobile devices with lower latency. It is a new architectural element that extends today’s cloud computing infrastructure.  Wikipedia     Cloudlet VS Cloud There is significant overlap in the requirements for cloud and cloudlet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Computes.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/computes-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/computes-io/</guid>
      <description>Computes.io is a mesh networked, distributed supercomputing platform powered by IPFS. Each node on the mesh network acts as both a core and kernel, meaning that each node can perform computations for other machines as well as request computations from itself and other machines.  computes.io     Computes.io is a distributed supercomputer mesh network. Each node on the mesh network acts as both a core and kernel — meaning that each node can perform Javascript computations for other machines as well as request computations from itself and other machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eywa</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/eywa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/fog-computing/eywa/</guid>
      <description>Eywa is an interoperable fog computing infrastructure for RDF Stream Processing (RSP). It implements a means of distribution and control of query workload for stream processing on flexible, interopeable, RDF graph structures.  eugenesiow.com     Paper Abstract Fog computing is an emerging technology for the Internet of Things (IoT) that aims to support processing on resource-constrained distributed nodes in between the sensors and actuators on the ground and compute clusters in the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FusionFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/fusionfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/fusionfs/</guid>
      <description>FusionFS is a distributed filesystem that co-exists with current parallel filesystems in High-End Computing, optimized for both a subset of HPC and Many-Task Computing workloads. FusionFS is a user-level filesystem that runs on the compute resource infrastructure, and enables every compute node to actively participate in the metadata and data management. Distributed metadata management is implemented using ZHT, a zero-hop distributed hashtable.  datasys.cs.iit.edu     Abstract State-of-the-art, yet decades-old, architecture of high-performance computing systems has its compute and storage resources separated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GlusterFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/glusterfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/glusterfs/</guid>
      <description>GlusterFS is a scale-out network-attached storage file system. It has found applications including cloud computing, streaming media services, and content delivery networks. GlusterFS was developed originally by Gluster, Inc. and then by Red Hat, Inc., as a result of Red Hat acquiring Gluster in 2011. Red Hat Gluster Storage is a GlusterFS-based Red Hat Storage Server.  Wikipedia         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HDFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/hdfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/hdfs/</guid>
      <description>The Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) is a distributed file system designed to run on commodity hardware. HDFS is highly fault-tolerant and is designed to be deployed on low-cost hardware. HDFS provides high throughput access to application data and is suitable for applications that have large data sets. HDFS relaxes a few POSIX requirements to enable streaming access to file system data.  apache.org         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermes</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/middleware/hermes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/middleware/hermes/</guid>
      <description>Hermes is a distributed, eventbased middleware platform. Hermes follows a type- and attribute-based publish/subscribe model that places particular emphasis on programming language integration by supporting type-checking of event data and event type inheritance. To handle dynamic, large-scale environments, Hermes uses peer-to-peer techniques for autonomic management of its overlay network of event brokers and for scalable event dissemination.  Pietzuch (2004). Hermes: A scalable event-based middleware. PhD Thesis.     A primary feature of the Hermes event-based middleware is scalability, as it is targeted at the development of large-scale distributed systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IPFS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/ipfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/ipfs/</guid>
      <description>InterPlanetary File System (IPFS) is a protocol designed to create a permanent and decentralized method of storing and sharing files. It is a content-addressable, peer-to-peer hypermedia distribution protocol. Nodes in the IPFS network form a distributed file system.  Wikipedia     IPNS IPFS has a name service called IPNS, a global namespace based on PKI, serves to build trust chains, is compatible with other NSes and can map DNS, .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lustre</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/lustre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/lustre/</guid>
      <description>Lustre is a type of parallel distributed file system, generally used for large-scale cluster computing. The name Lustre is a portmanteau word derived from Linux and cluster. Lustre file system software is available under the GNU GPLv2 and provides high performance file systems for computer clusters ranging in size from small workgroup clusters to large-scale, multi-site clusters.  Wikipedia and opensfs.org         HDFS iRODS Ceph GlusterFS Lustre     Architecture Centralized Centralized Distributed Decentralized Centralized   Naming Index Database CRUSH EHA Index   API CLI, FUSE, REST, API CLI, FUSE, API FUSE, mount, REST FUSE, mount FUSE   Fault detection Fully connect P2P Fully connect Detected Manually   System Availability No failover No failover High High Failover   Data availability Replication Replication Replication RAID-like No   Placement strategy Auto Manual Auto Manual No   Replication Async Sync Sync Sync RAID-like   Cache consistency WORM, lease Lock Lock No Lock   Load balancing Auto Manual Manual Manual No     Depardon et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PIOTRe</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/piotre/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/piotre/</guid>
      <description>PIOTRe is a Personal IoT Repository that allows applications to be built on interoperable and efficient semantic database technology for deployment on lightweight IoT devices. The name PIOTRe is derived from the name Peter meaning &amp;#39;stone&amp;#39; or &amp;#39;rock&amp;#39; and is the foundation for personal IoT device repositories.  cisco.com     Architecture 
 cisco.com    
PIOTRe PIOTRe is a Personal IoT Repository based on sparql2sql, sparql2stream and sparql2fed technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solid</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/solid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/decentralisation/solid/</guid>
      <description>Solid (derived from &amp;#39;social linked data&amp;#39;) is a proposed set of conventions and tools for building decentralized social applications based on Linked Data principles. The project aims to radically change the way Web applications work today, resulting in true data ownership as well as improved privacy.  computes.io     Apps  Plume Blogging
 Cimba Microblogging
 Contacts
 Dokieli Article Publishing
 Profile Editing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iRODS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/storage/irods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/storage/irods/</guid>
      <description>The integrated Rule-Oriented Data System (iRODS) is open source data management software used by research organizations and government agencies worldwide. iRODS is released as a production-level distribution aimed at deployment in mission critical environments. It virtualizes data storage resources, so users can take control of their data, regardless of where and on what device the data is stored. As data volumes grow and data services become more complex, iRODS is serving an increasingly important role in data management.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>