<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>App Protocols on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/</link>
    <description>Recent content in App Protocols on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CoAP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/coap/</guid>
      <description>CoAP is a specialised web transfer protocol for use with constrained nodes and constrained (e.g., low-power, lossy) networks.  RFC 7252     Research HTTP/2, CoAP on device HTTP/2 everywhere else, Security, Californium Cloud Services, MQTT vs CoAP, TinyOS Performance, Transport: Logistics
 
CoAP is network-oriented protocol with similar features to HTTP but also allows for low overhead, multicast, etc. CoAP operates over UDP (simpler) instead of TCP compensating for unreliability with a retransmission mechanism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/mqtt/</guid>
      <description>MQTT is a publish-subscribe-based lightweight messaging protocol for use on top of TCP/IP. It is designed for connections where a small code footprint is required or the network bandwidth is limited.  Wikipedia     Research CoAP vs MQTT, MQTT and REST, Push Notifications, Secure MQTT
 
MQTT-SN is a variation of the main protocol aimed at embedded devices on non-TCP/IP networks, such as ZigBee. As it does not require the TCP/IP stack, it can be used over a serial link where overhead is really small or over UDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>XMPP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/xmpp/</guid>
      <description>XMPP is a communications protocol for message-oriented middleware based on XML. It enables the near-real-time exchange of structured yet extensible data between any two or more network entities.  Wikipedia     Research IoT Deployment, Lightweight IoT Pub/Sub, SmartObjects with mDNS, Cryptographic Hashes
 
XMPP supports different communication patterns, such as Request/Response, Asynchronous Messaging, Publish/Subscribe, Event subscription (Observe) and Delayed delivery. XMPP also has support for different Quality of Service levels for messaging.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>