<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Research on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Research on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hermes</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/middleware/hermes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/middleware/hermes/</guid>
      <description>Hermes is a distributed, eventbased middleware platform. Hermes follows a type- and attribute-based publish/subscribe model that places particular emphasis on programming language integration by supporting type-checking of event data and event type inheritance. To handle dynamic, large-scale environments, Hermes uses peer-to-peer techniques for autonomic management of its overlay network of event brokers and for scalable event dissemination.  Pietzuch (2004). Hermes: A scalable event-based middleware. PhD Thesis.     A primary feature of the Hermes event-based middleware is scalability, as it is targeted at the development of large-scale distributed systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LinkSmart</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/middleware/linksmart/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/middleware/linksmart/</guid>
      <description>LinkSmart, formerly Hydra, is an open source IoT platform for developing IoT applications for various domains, such as Smart Cities, Industrie 4.0, Smart Grid and much more. The LinkSmart platform provides building blocks as generic and domain-specific services to efficiently implement applications in the Internet of Things. These include basic services such as device abstraction, data storage, live data management, and advanced ones such as stream mining and online machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIR</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/sir/</guid>
      <description>The Sensor Instance Registry (SIR) is a web service interface for managing sensor catalogues. It is based on the OGC discussion paper 10-171 and 09-163r2 (SensorML discovery profile) and presents a pragmatic solution that may serve as the basis for further discussion and development. The paper contains extensive descriptions of the service operations (requests and responses) for GET and POST requests.  52north.org     SensorML discovery profile (Paper) This Discussion Paper describes the mapping of sensor metadata encoded following SensorML specification 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>digrectory</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/digrectory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/digrectory/</guid>
      <description>A centralized infrastructure that allows registration of sensors. Employs &amp;#39;digrectory&amp;#39; to handle different resources. Each directory is attached to a particular communication technology, such as NFC, IPv6 etc. A mobile app enables users to discover and access sensors. Discovery mechanism takes advantage of geolocation and context awareness.  WoT Group     Architecture 
 
Architecture Components 
 
Abstract The application of Internet-enabled devices in the real world for the development of Smart Cities, environmental monitoring, bus tracking, and parking requires scalability, extensibility, and integration of emerging resources to reach a suitable ecosystem for data acquisition and interaction with citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>