<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mobile on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/mobile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mobile on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/mobile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beacon</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/beacon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/beacon/</guid>
      <description>Beacons are small devices that enable relatively accurate location within a narrow range (like indoors). Beacons periodically transmit small amounts of data within a range of approximately 70 meters, and are often used for indoor location technology.  Wikipedia     Research Smart Wearables Indoor Positioning, Indoor Positioning with Beacons
Health: Navigation for Wheelchair Users, GuideBeacon
 
iBeacon by Apple and Eddystone (formerly UriBeacon) by Google are 2 popular beacon technologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gps/</guid>
      <description>GPS provides geolocation and time information to a receiver anywhere on or near the Earth. It does not require the user to transmit any data, and it operates independently of any telephonic or internet reception.  Wikipedia     Research Stanford GPS Lab, Supply Chains, Indoor Navigation
 
Alternatives GLONASS is the most developed of the GPS alternatives, and is operated by Russia.
Quora article on alternatives.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gyroscope</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/gyroscope/</guid>
      <description>A gyroscope is a type of sensor useful for measuring orientation. Electronic, microchip-packaged MEMS gyroscopes are commonly found in consumer electronics devices.  Wikipedia     Research Health: Fall Detection, Hand Tremor
 
Accelerometers Though similar in purpose they measure different things. Gyroscopes determine orientation while accelerometers measure non-gravitational acceleration.
 
Inexpensive vibrating structure microelectromechanical systems (MEMS) gyroscopes have become widely available. These are packaged similarly to other integrated circuits and may provide either analog or digital outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedometer</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor/pedometer/</guid>
      <description>A pedometer is a device, usually portable and electronic or electromechanical, that counts each step a person takes by detecting the motion of the person&amp;#39;s hands or hips.  Wikipedia     Research Comparing 13 Pedometer Models, Accuracy for Children, How Many Steps Per Day?, Intensity Classification
 
Popular Devices Fitbit, Apple Watch, Nike+, iPod Nano
 
The technology for a pedometer includes a mechanical sensor and software to count steps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</guid>
      <description>Radio-frequency identification (RFID) uses electromagnetic fields to automatically identify and track tags, containing electronically stored information, attached to objects. There are passive and active tags.  Wikipedia     In 2009, Kevin Ashton, who cofounded the Auto-ID Center researching RFID, wrote an article in the RFID Journal titled &amp;ldquo;That &amp;lsquo;Internet of Things&amp;rsquo; Thing&amp;rdquo;. He is attributed with having coined the IoT term then.
 
Frequencies &amp;hellip;    Band Range Speed ~Tag$     LF 10cm Low $1   HF 10cm-1m Low &amp;gt;$0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>