<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Upnp on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/upnp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Upnp on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/upnp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SSDP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/ssdp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/ssdp/</guid>
      <description>The Simple Service Discovery Protocol (SSDP) is a network protocol based on the Internet Protocol Suite for advertisement and discovery of network services and presence information. It accomplishes this without assistance of server-based configuration mechanisms, such as the Dynamic Host Configuration Protocol (DHCP) or the Domain Name System (DNS), and without special static configuration of a network host.  Wikipedia     The Simple Service Discovery Protocol (SSDP) provides a mechanism where by network clients, with little or no static configuration, can discover network services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UPnP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/upnp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/discovery/upnp/</guid>
      <description>Universal Plug and Play (UPnP) is a set of networking protocols that permits networked devices, such as personal computers, printers, Internet gateways, Wi-Fi access points and mobile devices to seamlessly discover each other&amp;#39;s presence on the network and establish functional network services for data sharing, communications, and entertainment.  Wikipedia     Protocol UPnP assumes the network must run Internet Protocol (IP) and then leverages HTTP, SOAP and XML on top of IP, in order to provide device/service description, actions, data transfer and eventing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>