<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Smart Home on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/smart-home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Smart Home on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/smart-home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>HAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/han/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/han/</guid>
      <description>A home network or home area network (HAN) is a type of computer network that facilitates communication among devices within the close vicinity of a home. Devices capable of participating in this network, for example, smart devices such as network printers and handheld mobile computers, often gain enhanced emergent capabilities through their ability to interact.  Wikipedia     A home-area network (HAN) connects in-home digital devices, such as PCs, mobile phones, entertainment technology, thermostats, home security systems and smart appliances, into a common network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insteon</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/insteon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/insteon/</guid>
      <description>Insteon is a home automation technology that enables light switches, lights, thermostats, leak sensors, remote controls, motion sensors, and other electrically powered devices to interoperate through power lines, radio frequency (RF) communications, or both. It employs a dual-mesh networking topology in which all devices are peers and each device independently transmits, receives, and repeats messages.  Wikipedia     Insteon Hub Insteon Hub is a simple and straightforward device that connects you to your home from any smartphone or tablet, anywhere in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-Wave</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/z-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/z-wave/</guid>
      <description>Z-Wave is a wireless communications protocol used primarily for home automation. It is a mesh network using low-energy radio waves to communicate from appliance to appliance, allowing for wireless control of residential appliances and other devices, such as lighting control, security systems, thermostats, windows, locks, swimming pools and garage door openers.  Wikipedia     Essentials  Low Powered RF communications technology that supports full mesh networks without the need for a coordinator node</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>