<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Api on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Api on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resin.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/resin-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/resin-io/</guid>
      <description>Resin.io offers a development and deployment framework based upon Linux and containers that is designed to facilitate control of the on-device environment, provision devices on the network, and manage a fleet of systems.  resin.io     The Good  Developer friendly: iterate and push
 20 supported maker devices
 Container-based
 Open Source: ResinOS, Balena
 First 10 devices free
   
   Features &amp;hellip;     Control on-device environment   Provision devices easily   Manage device fleet at scale   Automate device fleet from own cloud   Encrypted communication   Continuous updates</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SensorCloud</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/sensorcloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/sensorcloud/</guid>
      <description>SensorCloud is a sensor data storage, visualization and remote management platform. It is a product of LORD MicroStrain Sensing Systems and leverages Cloud computing technologies to provide data scalability, rapid visualization, and user programmable analysis.  sensorcloud.com     MathEngine A $50/month per SensorCloud account account. It provides multiple ways to analyze data. It can generate FFT plots, filter out frequencies, and smooth out noisy data. It also integrates IPython Notebooks into its cloud service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>thethings.io</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/platform/thethings-io/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/platform/thethings-io/</guid>
      <description>thethings.iO is a Wayra Barcelona startup since July 2014 that makes a back-end for Internet of Things. It allows companies to focus more on the product and less on the database and the underlying cloud platform.  crunchbase     Featured In TechCrunch: thethings.iO Pulls In $270k
Forbes: 6 IoT Startups That Make Connecting Things To The Cloud A Breeze
VentureBeat: thethings.iO wants to be the Amazon Web Services for the IoT</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>