<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robotics on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/robotics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Robotics on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/robotics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EAPs</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/eap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/eap/</guid>
      <description>Electroactive polymers, or EAPs, are polymers that exhibit a change in size or shape when stimulated by an electric field. The most common applications of this type of material are in actuators and sensors. A typical characteristic property of an EAP is that they will undergo a large amount of deformation while sustaining large forces.  Wikipedia     Types  Dielectric
 Ferroelectric polymers
 Electrostrictive graft polymers</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Motor</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/motor/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/motor/</guid>
      <description>An engine or motor is a machine designed to convert one form of energy into mechanical energy. An electric motor is an electrical machine that converts electrical energy into mechanical energy. A stepper motor is a type of DC electric motor.  Wikipedia     Electric Motors Most electric motors operate through the interaction between an electric motor&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field and winding currents to generate force. Electric motors can be powered by direct current (DC) sources, such as from batteries, motor vehicles or rectifiers, or by alternating current (AC) sources, such as from the power grid, inverters or generators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/soft/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/actuator/soft/</guid>
      <description>Soft actuators are being developed to handle fragile objects like fruit harvesting in agriculture or manipulating the internal organs in biomedicine that has always been a challenging task for robotics. Unlike conventional actuators, soft actuators produce flexible motion due to the integration of microscopic changes at the molecular level into a macroscopic deformation of the actuator materials.  Wikipedia     PneuNets Bending Actuators PneuNets (pneumatic networks) are a class of soft actuator originally developed by the Whitesides Research Group at Harvard.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>