<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Specification on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/specification/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Specification on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/specification/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AMQP</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/amqp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/app-protocol/amqp/</guid>
      <description>The Advanced Message Queuing Protocol (AMQP) is an open standard application layer protocol for message-oriented middleware. The defining features of AMQP are message orientation, queuing, routing (including point-to-point and publish-and-subscribe), reliability and security.  Wikipedia     Architecture 
 
Network Protocol 
 
AMQP is a binary, application layer protocol, designed to efficiently support a wide variety of messaging applications and communication patterns. It provides flow controlled, message-oriented communication with message-delivery guarantees such as at-most-once (where each message is delivered once or never), at-least-once (where each message is certain to be delivered, but may do so multiple times) and exactly-once (where the message will always certainly arrive and do so only once), and authentication and/or encryption based on SASL and/or TLS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CoRE RD</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/core/</guid>
      <description>In many M2M applications, direct discovery of resources is not practical due to sleeping nodes, disperse networks, or networks where multicast traffic is inefficient. These problems can be solved by employing an entity called a Resource Directory (RD), which hosts descriptions of resources held on other servers, allowing lookups to be performed for those resources.  IETF.org Draft     Introduction The discovery of resources offered by a constrained server is very important in machine-to-machine applications where there are no humans in the loop and static interfaces result in fragility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypercat</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/hypercat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/hypercat/</guid>
      <description>The Hypercat specification allows Internet of Things (IoT) clients to discover information about IoT assets over the web. With Hypercat developers can write applications that will work across many servers, breaking down the walls between vertical silos.  Hypercat.io     Reference Server (Code)  GET, PUT, POST, DELETE of items
 Multi-search
 Geo search
 Lexicographic search
 Simple search
 Prefix search
 Authentication</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>