<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Radio on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/radio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Radio on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/radio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NFC</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/nfc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/nfc/</guid>
      <description>Near-field communication (NFC) is a set of communication protocols that enable two electronic devices, one of which is usually a portable device such as a smartphone, to establish communication by bringing them within 4 cm (1.6 in) of each other. NFC offers a low-speed connection with simple setup that can be used to bootstrap more capable wireless connections.  Wikipedia     NFC Protocol Stack Overview</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UWB</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/uwb/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/uwb/</guid>
      <description>Ultra-wideband (also known as UWB, ultra-wide band and ultraband) is a radio technology that can use a very low energy level for short-range, high-bandwidth communications over a large portion of the radio spectrum. UWB transmissions transmit information by generating radio energy at specific time intervals and occupying a large bandwidth, thus enabling pulse-position or time modulation.  Wikipedia     Ultra Wide Band (UWB) is a technology for the transmission of data using techniques which cause a spreading of the radio energy over a very wide frequency band, with a very low power spectral density.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zigbee</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</guid>
      <description>Zigbee is an IEEE 802.15.4-based specification for a suite of high-level communication protocols used to create personal area networks with small, low-power digital radios, such as for home automation, medical device data collection, and other low-power low-bandwidth needs, designed for small scale projects which need wireless connection.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.15.4 IEEE 802.15.4 is a technical standard which defines the operation of low-rate wireless personal area networks (LR-WPANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RFID</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:24:18 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/tag/rfid/</guid>
      <description>Radio-frequency identification (RFID) uses electromagnetic fields to automatically identify and track tags, containing electronically stored information, attached to objects. There are passive and active tags.  Wikipedia     In 2009, Kevin Ashton, who cofounded the Auto-ID Center researching RFID, wrote an article in the RFID Journal titled &amp;ldquo;That &amp;lsquo;Internet of Things&amp;rsquo; Thing&amp;rdquo;. He is attributed with having coined the IoT term then.
 
Frequencies &amp;hellip;    Band Range Speed ~Tag$     LF 10cm Low $1   HF 10cm-1m Low &amp;gt;$0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>