<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/arduino/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/arduino/</guid>
      <description>Arduino is an open source single-board microcontroller for building digital devices and interactive objects that can sense and control objects in the physical world. Arduino boards are available commercially in preassembled form, or as do-it-yourself kits.  Wikipedia     Research Agriculture: Soil Moisture Monitoring
Smart City/Smart Home: Smart Garbage, $30 Home Automation System, Environmental Monitoring
Industry: Smart Supply Chain
 
Series Comparison &amp;hellip;    Arduino CPU SRAM Flash     Yún 400 MHz 64 MB 16 MB   Uno 16 MHz 2 KB 32 KB   101 32 MHz 24 KB 196 KB   Micro 16 MHz 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beagle</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/beagle/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/beagle/</guid>
      <description>Beagles are low-cost, fan-less single-board computers based on low-power Texas Instruments processors featuring the ARM Cortex-A series core with all of the expandability of today&amp;#39;s desktop machines, but without the bulk, expense, or noise. Initially, development was targeted at enabling Linux distributions to improve support for ARM devices.  BeagleBoard.org     BeagleBone VS BeagleBone Black 
 elinux.org    
BeagleBoard The USB-powered BeagleBoard is a low-cost, fan-less single board computer that unleashes laptop-like performance and expandability without the bulk, expense, or noise of typical desktop machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CubieBoard</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/cubieboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/cubieboard/</guid>
      <description>Cubieboard is a single-board computer which can run Android 4 ICS, Ubuntu 12.04 desktop, Fedora 19 ARM Remix desktop, Arch Linux ARM, a Debian-based Cubian distribution, or OpenBSD. It uses the AllWinner A10 SoC, popular on cheap tablets, phones and media PCs. This SoC is used by developers of the lima driver, an open-source driver for the ARM Mali GPU.  Wikipedia     Cubietruck Plus (Cubieboard 5) Hardware (More Models)  SoC: Allwinner H8</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DASH7</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/dash7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/dash7/</guid>
      <description>DASH7 Alliance Protocol (D7A) is an open source Wireless Sensor and Actuator Network protocol, which operates in the 433 MHz, 868 MHz and 915 MHz unlicensed ISM band/SRD band. DASH7 provides multi-year battery life, range of up to 2 km, low latency for connecting with moving things, a very small open source protocol stack, AES 128-bit shared key encryption support, and data transfer of up to 167 kbit/s.  Wikipedia     Why DASH7?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gizmo2</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gizmo2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/kit/gizmo2/</guid>
      <description>Gizmo2 is the second generation open source x86 development board from GizmoSphere. Gizmo 2 provides the power of a high performance computer and the I/O capabilities of a microcontroller through the use of an AMD Embedded G-Series System-on-Chip (SOC). The board includes the AMD GX-210HA dual-core processor, combined on a single die with AMD Radeon HD 8210E discrete-class graphics, providing 85 GFLOPS performance while drawing only 9 watts TDP.  element14     The new Gizmo 2 platform is the second-generation x86-based DIY single-board-computer (SBC) from Gizmosphere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riot OS</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/os/riot/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/os/riot/</guid>
      <description>RIOT is a small operating system for networked, memory-constrained systems with a focus on low-power wireless IoT devices. It is open-source software, released under the GNU Lesser General Public License (LGPL). Due to its large independent community RIOT is often referred to as the Linux of the Internet of Things.  Wikipedia     RIOT is an operating system designed for the particular requirements of Internet of Things (IoT) scenarios.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>