<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sensor Networks on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sensor Networks on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bluetooth</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/bluetooth/</guid>
      <description>Bluetooth is a wireless technology standard for exchanging data over short distances (using short-wavelength UHF radio waves in the industrial, scientific and medical (ISM) radio bands from 2.4 to 2.485 GHz) from fixed and mobile devices, and building personal area networks (PANs). Bluetooth Low Energy or Smart is intended to provide considerably reduced power consumption and cost while maintaining a similar communication range.  Wikipedia     Feature Compare &amp;hellip;    Feature BT-LE BT     Audio/Headset No Yes   Data Yes Yes   A/V Control Non-Native Native   Throughput Low Medium   Authentication No For Non-Audio Only</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zigbee</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/zigbee/</guid>
      <description>Zigbee is an IEEE 802.15.4-based specification for a suite of high-level communication protocols used to create personal area networks with small, low-power digital radios, such as for home automation, medical device data collection, and other low-power low-bandwidth needs, designed for small scale projects which need wireless connection.  Wikipedia     IEEE 802.15.4 IEEE 802.15.4 is a technical standard which defines the operation of low-rate wireless personal area networks (LR-WPANs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>6LoWPAN</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/6lowpan/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/6lowpan/</guid>
      <description>The 6LoWPAN concept originated from the idea that &amp;#39;the Internet Protocol could and should be applied even to the smallest devices,&amp;#39; and that low-power devices with limited processing capabilities should be able to participate in the Internet of Things. The 6LoWPAN group has defined encapsulation and header compression mechanisms that allow IPv6 packets to be sent and received over IEEE 802.15.4 (LR-WPAN) based networks.  Wikipedia     Thread Thread is a standard suggested by Nest Labs based on IEEE 802.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ANT&#43;</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ant/</guid>
      <description>ANT&amp;#43; is a wireless protocol for monitoring sensor data such as a person&amp;#39;s heart rate or a car&amp;#39;s tyre/tire pressure, as well as the control of systems like indoor lighting or a television set.  Wikipedia     
 
ANT is a practical wireless sensor network protocol running in the 2.4 GHz ISM band. Designed for ultra-low power, ease of use, efficiency and scalability, ANT easily handles peer-to-peer, star, connected star, tree and fixed mesh topologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DASH7</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/dash7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/dash7/</guid>
      <description>DASH7 Alliance Protocol (D7A) is an open source Wireless Sensor and Actuator Network protocol, which operates in the 433 MHz, 868 MHz and 915 MHz unlicensed ISM band/SRD band. DASH7 provides multi-year battery life, range of up to 2 km, low latency for connecting with moving things, a very small open source protocol stack, AES 128-bit shared key encryption support, and data transfer of up to 167 kbit/s.  Wikipedia     Why DASH7?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IR</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/ir/</guid>
      <description>Infrared radiation, or simply infrared or IR, is electromagnetic radiation (EMR) with longer wavelengths than those of visible light, and is therefore invisible, although it is sometimes loosely called infrared light. IR data transmission is employed in short-range communication among computer peripherals and personal digital assistants.  Wikipedia     IrDA IrDA refers to a complete set of protocols for wireless infrared communications. The main reason for using IrDA had been wireless data transfer over the “last one meter” using point-and-shoot principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insteon</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/insteon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/insteon/</guid>
      <description>Insteon is a home automation technology that enables light switches, lights, thermostats, leak sensors, remote controls, motion sensors, and other electrically powered devices to interoperate through power lines, radio frequency (RF) communications, or both. It employs a dual-mesh networking topology in which all devices are peers and each device independently transmits, receives, and repeats messages.  Wikipedia     Insteon Hub Insteon Hub is a simple and straightforward device that connects you to your home from any smartphone or tablet, anywhere in the world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Z-Wave</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/z-wave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/sensor-network/z-wave/</guid>
      <description>Z-Wave is a wireless communications protocol used primarily for home automation. It is a mesh network using low-energy radio waves to communicate from appliance to appliance, allowing for wireless control of residential appliances and other devices, such as lighting control, security systems, thermostats, windows, locks, swimming pools and garage door openers.  Wikipedia     Essentials  Low Powered RF communications technology that supports full mesh networks without the need for a coordinator node</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>