<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Things Directories on DistributedFog</title>
    <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Things Directories on DistributedFog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CoRE RD</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/core/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/core/</guid>
      <description>In many M2M applications, direct discovery of resources is not practical due to sleeping nodes, disperse networks, or networks where multicast traffic is inefficient. These problems can be solved by employing an entity called a Resource Directory (RD), which hosts descriptions of resources held on other servers, allowing lookups to be performed for those resources.  IETF.org Draft     Introduction The discovery of resources offered by a constrained server is very important in machine-to-machine applications where there are no humans in the loop and static interfaces result in fragility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypercat</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/hypercat/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/hypercat/</guid>
      <description>The Hypercat specification allows Internet of Things (IoT) clients to discover information about IoT assets over the web. With Hypercat developers can write applications that will work across many servers, breaking down the walls between vertical silos.  Hypercat.io     Reference Server (Code)  GET, PUT, POST, DELETE of items
 Multi-search
 Geo search
 Lexicographic search
 Simple search
 Prefix search
 Authentication</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIR</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/sir/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/sir/</guid>
      <description>The Sensor Instance Registry (SIR) is a web service interface for managing sensor catalogues. It is based on the OGC discussion paper 10-171 and 09-163r2 (SensorML discovery profile) and presents a pragmatic solution that may serve as the basis for further discussion and development. The paper contains extensive descriptions of the service operations (requests and responses) for GET and POST requests.  52north.org     SensorML discovery profile (Paper) This Discussion Paper describes the mapping of sensor metadata encoded following SensorML specification 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>digrectory</title>
      <link>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/digrectory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:56:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://distributedfog.com/things-directory/digrectory/</guid>
      <description>A centralized infrastructure that allows registration of sensors. Employs &amp;#39;digrectory&amp;#39; to handle different resources. Each directory is attached to a particular communication technology, such as NFC, IPv6 etc. A mobile app enables users to discover and access sensors. Discovery mechanism takes advantage of geolocation and context awareness.  WoT Group     Architecture 
 
Architecture Components 
 
Abstract The application of Internet-enabled devices in the real world for the development of Smart Cities, environmental monitoring, bus tracking, and parking requires scalability, extensibility, and integration of emerging resources to reach a suitable ecosystem for data acquisition and interaction with citizens.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>